<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xml:lang="en" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/" xmlns:s="http://jadedpixel.com/-/spec/shopify">
  <id>https://audocph.com/blogs/news.atom</id>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://audocph.com/blogs/news"/>
  <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://audocph.com/blogs/news/tagged/audo-copenhagen.atom"/>
  <title>Audo Copenhagen - Connected Journal</title>
  <updated>2024-04-26T09:29:57+02:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Audo Copenhagen</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <id>https://audocph.com/blogs/news/organic-forms-and-industrial-precision</id>
    <published>2024-02-28T09:48:42+01:00</published>
    <updated>2024-02-29T03:27:36+01:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://audocph.com/blogs/news/organic-forms-and-industrial-precision"/>
    <title>Organic Forms and Industrial Precision</title>
    <author>
      <name>Audo Copenhagen</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<h2 style="text-align: center;">Known for his mastery in woodworking, New Zealand designer Ted Synnott ventures into uncharted territory with the Volume Side Table, a seamless fusion of natural forms and industrial sleekness.</h2>
<div style="text-align: center;"> </div>
<div style="text-align: center;">For Ted Synnott, the path to becoming a furniture designer was shaped by an array of influences. Born and raised on a farm in New Zealand, a love for creativity found its roots early on and his childhood years were characterised by a balance between athletic pursuits and creative endeavours, including painting with his aunt and making clothes with his mother.<br><br>
</div>
<div style="text-align: center;"></div>
<div style="text-align: center;">It wasn't until later in life that he discovered that working with hands was a particular strength and enrolled to study traditional timber furniture-making as a tangible outlet for his burgeoning ideas and the development of his practical skills. His journey continued with employment at several furniture companies and culminated in the establishment of his eponymous studio in 2019, marking the beginning of his independent and distinctive approach to furniture design.</div>
<div style="text-align: center;"></div>
<div style="text-align: center;">
<br>Without a formal design education, Ted’s knowledge is autonomous and largely shaped through online resources and books on the history and principles of design. A pivotal moment occurred during a visit to Europe in 2023 where he exhibited at the Stockholm Furniture Fair: the trip provided a complete sensory experience of the objects and spaces he had previously only abstracted through images.</div>
<div style="text-align: center;"></div>
<div style="text-align: center;">
<br>For Ted, good design is “<em>simple, functional and cost-effective to produce</em>.” Although he acknowledges this as an ideal and notes “<em>there is space and justification for things that focus more on beauty than pragmatism</em>.”</div>
<div style="text-align: center;"> </div>
<div style="text-align: center;"><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0262/3959/8658/files/IMG_6_journal_TS_1024x1024.png?v=1709113201" style="float: none;"></div>
<div style="text-align: center;"> </div>
<div style="text-align: center;">His design process is meticulous and thoughtful, focusing on a simplicity of form, a sensitivity to detail and a quest to find something different in the familiar. “<em>What I'm interested in continues to evolve but I really enjoy design that communicates clearly, regardless of the discipline. I like to think about the design process as looking in the same place as everyone else for something different</em>,” he avers.</div>
<div style="text-align: center;"></div>
<div style="text-align: center;">
<br>“<em>I often labour over ideas for considerable time before finally bringing them to life. I’m always considering how things will be produced, which dictates the ideas I pursue. I enjoy exploring materials and manufacturing techniques to expand my possible output.</em>”</div>
<div style="text-align: center;"></div>
<div style="text-align: center;">
<br>While wood offers familiarity, warmth and tactility, Ted finds metals ”<em>exacting, sanitary, easy to maintain and indifferent to most climatic conditions</em>.” Most of his furniture is shaped from timber but  he has been working increasingly with metals.</div>
<div style="text-align: center;"></div>
<div style="text-align: center;">
<br>“<em>Metals in general are well suited to industrial production as they are standardised, ubiquitous, uniform in appearance and typically require less post-processing work than organic materials. Aluminium has the added benefits of being infinitely recyclable—without loss of material of quality—as well being impervious to rust because it contains no iron,</em>” he explains.</div>
<div style="text-align: center;"> </div>
<div style="text-align: center;"><img style="float: none;" alt="" src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0262/3959/8658/files/IMG_4_journal_TS_1024x1024.png?v=1709110009"></div>
<div style="text-align: center;"> </div>
<div style="text-align: center;">Loose sheet paper sketches transform into cohesive collections through a gradual amalgamation of details and concepts, resulting in a final product that often reflects his deep connection to traditional wood craftsmanship: “<em>Because I have more experience in timber than paper or card, I tend to go straight to the end point, for better or for worse</em>.”</div>
<div style="text-align: center;"></div>
<div style="text-align: center;">
<br>And while wood holds a special place, Ted’s exploration of stone and metal adds diversity to his practice and he embraces the inherent qualities of each material, the latter most notably on the Volume Side Table.</div>
<div style="text-align: center;"></div>
<div style="text-align: center;">
<br>Emerging from an encounter while drawing, the Volume Side Table is distinctly different when viewed from each of its four sides. Stumbling upon the form while drawing cubes as a pause to think of new ideas, Ted rounded some edges and realised that the shape tessellated in three dimensions. “<em>This is a lot of what appeals about it to me, it's unintuitive and invites closer inspection. Universal familiarity with primary shapes makes the design broadly appealing, while its subtle deviation from expectation piques interest,</em>” he notes.</div>
<div style="text-align: center;"></div>
<div style="text-align: center;">
<br>“<em>Timber has individual character and variation that are both good and bad when producing larger quantities. On one hand, it differentiates each unit of production through a unique grain pattern and tone. But these appealing differences also add complication at an industrial scale as idiosyncratic timber grain may require different processing than another. Wood movement, as it absorbs and releases moisture, and orientation also needs to be considered throughout the design process whereas metal changes size comparatively little in response to humidity or heat.</em>”</div>
<div style="text-align: center;"> </div>
<div style="text-align: center;"><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0262/3959/8658/files/IMG_7_journal_TS_1024x1024.png?v=1709113226" style="float: none;"></div>
<div style="text-align: center;"> </div>
<div style="text-align: center;">As a series of tessellating planes, it was logical to Ted to make it from sheet metal and aluminium was chosen for its uniformity and workability. ”Once welded, ground and brushed, the uniform surface makes it appear as a homogenous whole, like stone or silver bullion rather than an object of multiple pieces. This cohesive appearance lends the table a feeling of permanence,” he adds.</div>
<div style="text-align: center;"></div>
<div style="text-align: center;">
<br>Looking to the future, Ted believes the rise of AI tools will reshape the industry and the role of designers. “<em>People will be overwhelmed by an abundance of AI-generated content in the digital realm and designers will need to work collaboratively with these tools, filtering the mass of information and deciding which ideas to develop from digital data into physical matter,” he notes, adding that while this shifting landscape will undoubtedly change our approach, “the physical world maintains immutable characteristics and constraints that all new ideas still need to abide by.</em>”</div>
<div style="text-align: center;"> </div>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://audocph.com/blogs/news/passages-of-life</id>
    <published>2023-07-07T10:49:37+02:00</published>
    <updated>2023-12-21T08:42:00+01:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://audocph.com/blogs/news/passages-of-life"/>
    <title>Passages of Life</title>
    <author>
      <name>Audo Copenhagen</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<div style="text-align: center;">
<h3>Audo Copenhagen’s new retail space presents an intimate exploration of the home.</h3>
<p> </p>
</div>
<div style="text-align: center;"></div>
<p style="text-align: center;">Reflecting the desire for a more personalised shopping experience, the new Audo Concept Shop in Copenhagen evokes a sense of familiarity, relaxation and connection as a retail space that feels like home. <br>Together with Christian Møller Andersen, artistic director at Kinfolk, the dramatic transformation from static design store to familiar residential space taps into the spirit that defines Audo Copenhagen, placing focus on community, softly minimal design and innovative thinking. <br> <br> <img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0262/3959/8658/files/IMG_1_1024x1024.jpg?v=1688652788" style="float: none;"> </p>
<div style="text-align: center;">“We wanted to create something intimate and personal—more like a home than a traditional shop,” says Andersen of the space at Audo House in Copenhagen. Setting out to rethink how it could become more experiential and sensorial, where once was an open space with no obvious beginning or end, today Audo Concept Shop encourages exploration and discovery as customers wind their way through a series of rooms, each with their own character and furnished with the objects that would commonly be found there.
<p>“The shop layout resembles a home, with different "rooms" that emulate the feel of a hallway, living room, dining room, study and dressing room,” Andersen explains. “This layout creates a sense of familiarity and encourages customers to explore and interact with the products in a more intimate setting that feels more relevant, more inspiring.”</p>
<p> </p>
<p><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0262/3959/8658/files/IMG_2_1024x1024.png?v=1688652888" style="float: none;"></p>
<p> </p>
<p>Throughout the space, custom made oak shelves display Audo Copenhagen’s offerings and artful tomes alongside a host of other design objects available for purchase, including artworks that adorn the walls. “It was important to look away from the traditional in-store way of grouping objects in neat rows and instead display them in situ, as one would in the home,” he notes.</p>
<p>The clever use of residential-style furniture includes sofas, armchairs, coffee tables and lamps to provide customers with familiar and comfortable living areas that resonate with personal preferences to enhance the feeling of just how these would work in their own home.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0262/3959/8658/files/IMG_4_1024x1024.png?v=1688652948" alt=""> </p>
<p>Warm and natural materials and colours, such as wood, stone and saturated earthy tones that demarcate each room, help to create a cosy and welcoming ambience that makes customers feel at ease while browsing.</p>
<p>“Moving away from traditional Nordic colours gives the space more character. While inspired by palazzos in Italy and the colours of the Mediterranean, the hues selected for the walls nod to our Danish cultural heritage too: they reference Modernist furniture from the 1950s and 60s and Copenhagen’s Thorvaldsen Museum. It is Scandinavian design history through a modern lens,” notes Andersen. “The colours are cohesive yet divide the space into separate rooms, each with its own unique expression.”</p>
<p> </p>
<p><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0262/3959/8658/files/IMG_3_christian_1024x1024.png?v=1688719543" alt="">  </p>
<p>Wanting to “give visitors to Audo House an experience beyond the ordinary,” Audo Concept Shop fosters the same sense of community Audo Copenhagen is noted for, as a space to host events, exhibitions or gatherings that bring like-minded individuals together. This versatility allows the shop to serve as a social hub beyond just a retail space, offering a consistent experience to ensure that visitors feel a seamless connection with Audo Copenhagen. “Ultimately, we hope that customers will explore the space with all their senses. Touch objects and use them. Don’t walk around on tiptoes: sit in a chair, relax on a sofa, try things out and stay for a while,” Andersen concludes.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><em>Discover the Audo Concept Shop at Århusgade 130 in Copenhagen.</em> </p>
</div>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://audocph.com/blogs/news/3daysofdesign-2023</id>
    <published>2023-06-20T11:30:00+02:00</published>
    <updated>2023-12-21T08:42:00+01:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://audocph.com/blogs/news/3daysofdesign-2023"/>
    <title>3daysofdesign 2023 at Audo</title>
    <author>
      <name>Audo Copenhagen</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<h3 style="padding-left: 30px; text-align: center;"></h3>
<h3 style="padding-left: 30px; text-align: center;">It was truly a pleasure to witness everyone coming together for 3daysofdesign at the Audo House, sharing their love for design and engaging in insightful conversations and <i>meaningful connections</i>.</h3>
<p> </p>
<p><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0262/3959/8658/files/IMG_5_1024x1024.png?v=1687177045" alt=""></p>
<div style="text-align: center;"></div>
<h3 style="padding-left: 30px; text-align: center;"></h3>
<h3 style="padding-left: 30px; text-align: center;"></h3>
<h3 style="padding-left: 30px; text-align: center;"></h3>
<h3 style="padding-left: 30px; text-align: center;">
<br><b>Eclectic Enchantment<br></b><i>New upholstery on Audo designs</i>
</h3>
<p> </p>
<div style="padding-left: 30px; text-align: center;">Our classic and contemporary furniture designs decorating Audo House were for 3daysofdesign swathed in an eclectic mix of upholstery fabrics by Dedar, Christian Lacroix (by Designers Guild) and Kelly Wearstler, among others. <br> <br><a href="https://presscloud.com/file/93/935633050577429/PL_Upholstery_program_EU.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><i>View our upholstery </i><i>programme<br><br><br></i> </a>
</div>
<div style="padding-left: 30px; text-align: center;"><i></i></div>
<div style="padding-left: 30px; text-align: center;"><i></i></div>
<div style="padding-left: 30px; text-align: center;"><i></i></div>
<div style="padding-left: 30px; text-align: center;"><i></i></div>
<div style="padding-left: 30px; text-align: center;"><i></i></div>
<div style="padding-left: 30px; text-align: center;"><i></i></div>
<div style="padding-left: 30px; text-align: center;"><i><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0262/3959/8658/files/img_1_1024x1024.png?v=1687172549" style="float: none;"></i></div>
<div style="padding-left: 30px; text-align: center;"><i></i></div>
<div style="padding-left: 30px; text-align: center;"><i><b></b></i></div>
<div style="padding-left: 30px; text-align: center;"><i><b></b></i></div>
<div style="padding-left: 30px; text-align: center;"><i><b></b></i></div>
<h3 style="padding-left: 30px; text-align: center;"><i><b></b></i></h3>
<h3 style="padding-left: 30px; text-align: center;">
<i><b><br></b></i><b>Passages of Life</b><i><b><br> </b>Audo Concept Shop</i>
</h3>
<div style="text-align: center;"></div>
<div style="text-align: center;">
<br> Artistic and inviting, the new Audo Concept Shop, curated by Christian Møller Andersen, is an intimate exploration of the home. Discover the different moments of life as you pass through a series of inspiring spaces created to put in practice classic and contemporary design. Discover the Audo Concept Shop located at Århusgade 130, 2150 Nordhavn, Denmark.<br><br> </div>
<div style="text-align: center;"></div>
<div style="text-align: center;"><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0262/3959/8658/files/IMG_2_1024x1024.jpg?v=1687173828" alt=""></div>
<h3 style="text-align: center;">
<br><b><br>Fence Installation<br> </b><i>by Colin King and Alex Crowder</i>
</h3>
<p> </p>
<div style="text-align: center;">Imaginative, sculptural arrangements transformed the Audo Residence's Grand Room into an immersive installation where Stance Vases from our Colin King Collection filled with seasonal flowers became a living lesson in design and botany.<br><br>
</div>
<div style="text-align: center;"></div>
<div style="text-align: center;"></div>
<div style="text-align: center;"><a href="https://audocph.com/products/stance-vase"><i>Discover the Stance Vases<br><br></i></a></div>
<div style="text-align: center;"><i></i></div>
<div style="text-align: center;"><i> </i></div>
<div style="text-align: center;"><i></i></div>
<p style="text-align: center;"> <i><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0262/3959/8658/files/IMG_3_1024x1024.png?v=1687174270" alt=""></i></p>
<h3 style="text-align: center;">
<br><b>Arranging Things<br></b><i>Colin King book signing</i>
</h3>
<p> </p>
<div style="text-align: center;">
<p>At this year’s 3daysofdesign, the New York-based stylist and designer Colin King joined us at Audo House to sign the first edition of his new book, Arranging Things. King also shared his insights on cultivating beauty in the everyday through carefully curated compositions of objects, while Audo’s brand and design director, Joachim Kornbek Engell-Hansen, joined the conversation sharing his thoughts on design, interior styling and their collaboration.</p>
<p><a href="https://audocph.com/collections/colin-king"><i>Discover our Colin King collection</i></a></p>
<p> </p>
<p><i><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0262/3959/8658/files/IMG_4_1024x1024.jpg?v=1687174723" style="float: none;"></i></p>
<p> </p>
<h3>
<b>A </b><b>Sense of Community<br> </b><i>celebrating a new chapter<br><br></i>
</h3>
<p>Nothing is more precious than human connection and we believe that wherever there is space, there is always an opportunity for community.</p>
<p>On 1 June 2023, Audo Copenhagen was launched by uniting MENU and by Lassen under a single roof. This year’s 3daysofdesign has been the ideal opportunity to inaugurate this new chapter, as we welcomed friends, partners, customers and design enthusiasts at Audo House.<br> <br> A sense of community empowers us to create <i>better</i>.</p>
<p> </p>
 </div>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0262/3959/8658/files/IMG_6_1024x1024.png?v=1687177069" style="float: none;"></p>
<div style="text-align: center;"><i></i></div>
<div style="padding-left: 30px; text-align: center;"><i></i></div>
<div style="padding-left: 30px; text-align: center;"><i></i></div>
<div><i></i></div>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://audocph.com/blogs/news/built-for-trade</id>
    <published>2022-11-24T08:53:24+01:00</published>
    <updated>2023-12-27T11:57:06+01:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://audocph.com/blogs/news/built-for-trade"/>
    <title>Built for Trade</title>
    <author>
      <name>Audo Copenhagen</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<h3>A statue of Mercury cast in bronze has graced the historic Oslo Stock Exchange for more than 100 years, symbolising wealth, good fortune and commerce. As part of the major rehabilitation project by Tuvalu architects, the statue has reassumed a central position in the interior layout. The Merkur chair, created for the building and named for its symbolic figure, populates an updated, central stock exchange and joins the Audo collection with design by Skogstad &amp; Wærnes.</h3>
<p style="text-align: start;"><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0262/3959/8658/files/Merkur_Journal_2_1024x1024.png?v=1668684933" alt="" style="float: none;"></p>
<p> </p>
<p>Oslo Stock Exchange history goes back to 1823 when the architect Christian H. Grosch's proposal was accepted for construction. The building project was an exceptional undertaking, completed on the site of Grønningen, the first public park in Christiania. On its completion in 1828, Oslo Stock Exchange was called Norway's first monumental building.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>The structure was extended in 1910 by architect Carl Michaelsen, executed in the Empire style with added elements of Neoclassicism. Over the next one hundred years, the Oslo Stock Exchange underwent many changes, both operationally and aesthetically. It evolved from a commodity exchange to a marketplace for shares and securities. Some of its interior spaces have remained well-preserved historic rooms featuring a broad mix of materials, ornamentation and symbolic elements. Other rooms were repeatedly converted, especially in the 1980s.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0262/3959/8658/files/Merkur_Journal_3_1024x1024.png?v=1668685032" alt="" style="float: none;"></p>
<p>In 2019, Norweigan architecture firm Tuvalu was chosen to lead the total rehabilitation of the stock exchange, a large-scale modernization with respect to the building’s origin and future. Designers Petter Skogstad and Fredrik Wærnes of Skogstad &amp; Wærnes were asked to design a chair for the new exchange, a core element to the function and visual identity of the interior.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>As the Oslo Stock Exchange is, in fact, the only Nordic stock exchange in the Euronext portfolio, it was important for the chair design to reflect Norwegian as well as Nordic identity. The interconnection between Nordic countries and design posed the obvious question ‘What is Nordic design?’ What followed was an examination of the distinct features of Danish, Norwegian, Swedish, Finish and Icelandic, as well as the Faroe, Greenlandic, and Ålandic design.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0262/3959/8658/files/Merkur_Journal_4_1024x1024.png?v=1668685066" alt="" style="float: none;"></p>
<p> </p>
<p>Handcraft and transparent construction, common to Nordic design traditions, became important. Honest joinery was important to the design construction, an element of traditional Norwegian craft as well as Danish design. The goal was a classic and modern design with character, a difficult harmony to achieve but an interesting design challenge for Skogstad &amp; Wærnes.</p>
<p> </p>
<h3>“We wanted the chair to be a kind of tribute to the historic chairs within the building,” says Wærnes.</h3>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
<p><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0262/3959/8658/files/Merkur_Journal_5_1024x1024.png?v=1668685103" alt="" style="float: none;"></p>
<p> </p>
<p>Old fiddle back chairs from historic photographs of the Oslo Stock Exchange were a key reference in the design process. Playing with this inspiration allowed the design to take shape as a historical link to the Oslo Stock Exchange with modern soul. Petter Skogstad and Fredrik Wærnes wanted this chair to be both specific to the site while also possessing the power to fit other contexts. They pursued a design that could move beyond its intended space into private homes, businesses and cultural sites internationally.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>Beautiful carpentry, honest joinery and elements from traditional Norwegian and Nordic design styles combine to exude subtle strength and confidence. Solid wood construction and the fiddle backrest make the chair historically rooted and forward-facing, while the curved backrest and arms make it comfortable and supportive. Aesthetically, the size and proportions of the Merkur chair design make it traditional yet contemporary, expressive but not messy.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0262/3959/8658/files/Merkur_Journal_7_1024x1024.png?v=1668685166" alt="" style="float: none;"></p>
<p>Naturally, this chair is also deeply connected to the Oslo Stock Exchange, referencing the buildings’ previous chairs and complimenting its architectural character. To this effect, the first Merkur chairs produced have been numbered 1-100 and sit on the Oslo Stock Exchange floor where they support trade and commerce daily.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>The Merkur launches January 2023 in solid oak and black painted oak, with and without armrests.</p>
<p> </p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0262/3959/8658/files/Merkur_Journal_6_1024x1024.png?v=1668685526" alt="" style="float: none;"></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://audocph.com/blogs/news/living-design</id>
    <published>2022-09-09T10:46:23+02:00</published>
    <updated>2023-12-27T11:57:07+01:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://audocph.com/blogs/news/living-design"/>
    <title>Living Design</title>
    <author>
      <name>Audo Copenhagen</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<h2>From Nina Bruun’s eponymous design studio comes Epoch, a collection of functional interior objects made from natural materials.</h2>
<p>Since starting her own design studio in 2016, Nina Bruun has barely stood still. The award-winning designer has garnered numerous design accolades – including a prestigious Red Dot Design Award. She is represented in the permanent exhibition at the Museum of Arts and Design in New York and is a jury member of the German Design Counsel. And she has a string of successful designs under her belt. The latest from her hand is Epoch – <a href="https://menuspace.com/collections/hangers" title="Design hangers, hooks and shelfs">a clothing rack and shelf </a>respectively, designed exclusively for Audo.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;" data-mce-style="text-align: left;"><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0262/3959/8658/files/NB_2_1024x1024.jpg?v=1659523366" alt="" style="float: none;" data-mce-style="float: none;"></p>
<p>The Epoch Collection stems from the coat rack and the idea of ​​concealing unsightly hangers and tags behind something beautiful. “I wanted to take the idea of ​​improving and beautifying a very well-known product further, developing a shelf and coat rack using a beautiful, wide band of wood. I like the idea of creating a simple form with simple functionality as simply as possible,” Nina notes.</p>
<p>The minimally elegant <a href="https://audocph.com/products/epoch-rack" data-mce-href="https://audocph.com/products/epoch-rack">Epoch Clothes Rack</a> and <a href="https://audocph.com/products/epoch-shelf" data-mce-href="https://audocph.com/products/epoch-shelf">Epoch Shelf</a> were developed and perfected gradually, at an unhurried pace that suits Bruun’s methodical nature. Characterised by soft bands of undulating wood that sit like sculptures on a wall, the Epoch Collection nods to the 1950s with its pure form, natural materials and subtle craftsmanship. Despite their differences, both shelf and rack are coherent in design and carefully sized to fit both purpose and place.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;" data-mce-style="text-align: left;"><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0262/3959/8658/files/NB_3_1024x1024.jpg?v=1659523408" alt="" style="float: none;" data-mce-style="float: none;"></p>
<p>Believing clean lines, intuitive function and innate beauty as fundamental to good design, Bruun also wanted to create a lasting, high-quality object that could easily interact with other items. “These are pieces for still life displays, for everything we love to surround ourselves with – whether that’s objects or clothing. I’d like to see them used individually and hung over one other in a column-like formation. But most of all, I’d like to see them being used in personal and creative ways,” she concludes.</p>
<p><a href="https://audocph.com/collections/nina-bruun" data-mce-href="https://audocph.com/collections/nina-bruun">Explore Nina Bruun's design for Audo here</a>.</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://audocph.com/blogs/news/balancing-act</id>
    <published>2022-08-10T11:33:29+02:00</published>
    <updated>2023-12-21T08:42:48+01:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://audocph.com/blogs/news/balancing-act"/>
    <title>Balancing Act</title>
    <author>
      <name>Audo Copenhagen</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<h2>Dancer turned designer Colin King plays with magic and meaning with Interconnect, his bold candle holder for Audo.</h2>
<p>Professionally trained as a dancer, Colin King found himself at the intersection between a dancer’s awareness of space and a stylist’s impulse to bring it to life before foraying into the realm of product design. Currently based in Tribeca, New York City, he finds himself in a balance between being on set, styling and designing from his studio. Colin has styled for major publications such as Architectural Digest and T Magazine and hosts a myriad clientele within the genres of product and interior design. He is continuously inspired by life’s everyday rituals, gestures and imperfections – made beautiful by their ever-evolving presence within a given space. We spoke with the multi-talent about his interest in design and the year-long process to create Interconnect, Audo's latest <a href="https://menuspace.com/collections/candle-holders" title="Contemporary candelholders">candle holder design</a>.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0262/3959/8658/files/Colin_King_1_bw_c36998b8-ee90-495d-b0ee-f064f034dfb8_1024x1024.jpg?v=1666769024" alt=""></p>
<div style="text-align: left;"></div>
<h3></h3>
<h3>When did you first develop an interest in design?</h3>
<p>“I don’t know there ever was a fixed beginning, but the one thing that has been consistent is the use of a camera to capture a way of seeing. With a camera it takes constant practice to find the feeling or arrangement of objects and translate them into a two-dimensional image. This is the endless practice I have grown from; taking something you experience and arranging and rearranging it until it’s translated into an image that binds a feeling.”</p>
<h3>
<br>And how have you come to work with design?</h3>
<p>“Technically, I have no proper design education. It has just been self-taught through hours at museums and galleries and time spent flipping through books. The way I approach design is so much looser than the industry ‘standard.’ Styling and photography have shaped my design process, so I often feel like a hybrid creative. Above being a designer, I am first and foremost a student: the more I learn, the less I feel I can box myself into one singular title.”</p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0262/3959/8658/files/CK_3_1024x1024.jpg?v=1659522922" alt="" style="float: none;"></p>
<h3>
<br>What has shaped your design principles and philosophy?</h3>
<p>“Growing up in rural Ohio, I’ve always had an appreciation of nature and grew up feeling a close connection to it. Beyond that, being a dancer taught me discipline and gave me a vocabulary beyond speech; it taught me spatial awareness and the ability to translate one sense into another. I learned to quickly pick up on visual nuance because when you train, you’re expected to learn combinations almost immediately.</p>
<p><br>There’s a connection between loving nature and learning to dance. So often I find myself somewhere in between the two: completing a line, a gesture, an intent or an emotion.”</p>
<h3>
<br>Who or what has been most influential to your creativity?</h3>
<p>“We’re all so shaped by our experiences and the many people who enter our lives over the course of time. From dance teachers to college professors, those who saw in me that which I couldn’t see in myself. These characters in my life encouraged me to pursue a career I never thought I could have. And mentors have a unique relationship with borrowed confidence. This is their gift to us during the times we need it to grow.”</p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0262/3959/8658/files/CK_4_1024x1024.jpg?v=1659522948" alt="" style="float: none;"></p>
<h3>
<br>What constitutes good design?</h3>
<p>“Good design happens when you have a room that just feels like if you moved or took anything away it would be incomplete. A good edit – a calculated sense of restraint – shows us when to leave an idea just as it is. [Good design] also lives in the contrast of materials. Within the mix of unlikely companions and newly formed perspectives is when you see an ensemble in a new light and think, “I love that,” even when you were about to leave it behind. I think that’s where the best kind of design comes from.”</p>
<h3>
<br>Tell us about how you approach your work as a designer.</h3>
<p>“It usually begins with a visual reference – a jumping off point. Combing through archives of saved imagery in a vast collection of books. Each time I flip through them with a different project in mind I see something I haven't seen before – or I see it in a new light. The next step is to save some space. I try not to over plan. There has to be room to build and let a project breathe to leave room for a surprise encounter or a happy accident. And when it all comes together, there’s a new sense of self-trust. The next time risk or chance comes your way, it’s always a bit easier to let it in.”</p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0262/3959/8658/files/CK_5_1024x1024.jpg?v=1659522967" alt="" style="float: none;"></p>
<h3>
<br>What is your signature design philosophy?</h3>
<p>“Nature humbles me and reminds me to abandon perfection. There’s a lot of beauty to be found in unexpected places. Scale reminds me of this, too. If I can play with exaggerations without losing practicality, then I know I’m chasing a necessary balance. There’s always a middle ground between control and le tting go – and nothing should feel too modern or too classic. We are visited by lessons on balance throughout life, so it’s only natural to let that influence any philosophy behind creating.”</p>
<h3>
<br>What’s the best part of your job?</h3>
<p>“The best part of any job is working alongside other creatives. People are always at the heart of the projects I love most. But I can’t deny that, being a stylist, it is always amazing to be in really well-designed homes. And the moment you step back and see the work of your hands, the result of a team, the photos from a shoot, it’s like a bookmark to another chapter.”</p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0262/3959/8658/files/CK_6_1024x1024.jpg?v=1659522994" alt="" style="float: none;"></p>
<h3>
<br>Which artists and designers have been most influential to your work?</h3>
<p>“Vilhelm Hammershøi and Johannes Vermeer have played a very influential role in my work. Within these pieces there’s a sense of light and atmosphere that feels intimate and there’s something about it that draws you in – the darkness of it. I also love works by Giorgio Morandi, Isamu Noguchi and Alexander Calder. Within these pieces there’s a playful use of movement and geometry that inspires a sense of balance.”</p>
<h3>
<br>And are there other creative fields that inform your work?</h3>
<p>“Photography, art, film... I’m always amazed by the ‘makers’ – people who create with their hands. Those who take the mundane and make it beautiful. Those who have the confidence to express themselves and who are fearless with who they are. Music is also an informer. It can take you to a different place and time, or help you to stay grounded in the present.”</p>
<p> </p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0262/3959/8658/files/CK_7_1024x1024.png?v=1659523015" alt="" style="float: none;"></p>
<h3>
<br>What inspired you to create Interconnect?</h3>
<p>“As a stylist, I love the idea of a candle holder, but it always fell short through the lens of the camera. I started off with scale and knew I wanted to create something with a real presence. Something with expanse that can live on its own or with other objects. The idea of it being able to be used as a sculpture that looks as good with or without a candle being lit was important. I wanted to create something that would have a life of its own beyond its intended use.”</p>
<h3>
<br>How long did it take to develop?</h3>
<p>“Almost a year. And it’s a totally different experience for me. As a stylist, part of my job is to be decisive and to be the one who says, “yes this looks good.” It’s not only a part of my job, but also is literally what people pay me for. So to have to dwell in a place of decision-making for a year is a big leap. It’s a commitment that requires trust in the initial idea and to see it through. But I genuinely mean it when I say it’s been an amazing experience. To hold hands with these early concepts and then see them come to life has been very humbling and rewarding.”</p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0262/3959/8658/files/CK_8_981e4e11-32fd-4c8a-a15b-0269bcab2cd4_1024x1024.jpg?v=1659523040" alt="" style="float: none;"></p>
<h3>
<br>What influenced the style of it?</h3>
<p>“Geometry and dramatic proportions. In my eyes, there are faultless, basic principles of geometry. The shapes that represent this well are a sphere, an angle and a line. Simple forms become exaggerated and what emerges is an object with a simplicity that speaks volumes.”</p>
<h3>
<br>What considerations did you have when designing it?</h3>
<p>“The shape, of course, was a main focus. It was important to get the proportion of the base right with the slenderness of the stem. The angles of where pieces meet and then depart play a huge role, too. Materiality was a total learning curve and was a really amazing experience to work through with the Audo Team. There is a total consideration for sustainability and not creating too much waste when producing these candle holders. How can moulds be used without excess. But there’s also a consideration of longevity. I needed to create a piece that could travel and not be too precious. To have enough strength to be used. To grow and grow with. This is a sculptural piece that has weight and grows in beauty with every nick or scratch or remaining piece of wax from a candle that’s been lit.“</p>
<h3>
<br>How do you see it being used?</h3>
<p>“I do feel this is an object with multiple uses overall. Whether as a sculpture alone or with a candle, keep it fun –the most exciting part about designing a product is to see how people use it in ways I never could have imagined. I see it being used on the floor, bedside, dining, mantle shelving, coffee table. It’s a li ttle specific, but opening up a book and placing it underneath, with the spill of the evening light... There's a lot of magic to be played with and I can’t wait to see how people imagine its place in their homes. Beyond its intended use, Interconnect carries time, nature, the way we used to see by a candle’s flame, into a new sense of meaning where light – or even the absence of it – is upheld with simple purity and shaped encounters.”</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://audocph.com/blogs/news/daniel-schofield-his-design-process-and-the-ray-table-lamp</id>
    <published>2022-07-21T13:05:09+02:00</published>
    <updated>2023-12-27T11:57:06+01:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://audocph.com/blogs/news/daniel-schofield-his-design-process-and-the-ray-table-lamp"/>
    <title>Daniel Schofield: His design process and the Ray Table Lamp</title>
    <author>
      <name>Audo Copenhagen</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<h2>
<strong></strong>With a background in graphic design and carpentry, the award-winning designer Daniel Schofield looks to the beauty in simplicity, exploring materials and techniques to create characterful yet pared back pieces with life-enhancing function. We met with the Copenhagen-based British designer for a chat about his practice and the new <a href="https://menuspace.com/products/ray-table-lamp-portable">Ray Table Lamp</a> for Audo, an homage to his grandfather and the versatility of light.</h2>
<div style="text-align: center;"><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0262/3959/8658/files/GS_1_1024x1024.jpg?v=1658303673" alt="" none=""></div>
<h3>Tell us a little about your background.</h3>
<p>My schoolteacher suggested I studied graphic design at college as I was good at art. It was good, but I wanted to do something more physical, so I signed up to a carpentry apprenticeship, building houses, offices and hotels. After some time, I wanted something more creative and a family friend taught me woodturning while another friend mentioned a furniture and product design course and I thought “why not?” I absolutely loved it.</p>
<p> </p>
<h3>How did you get into design?</h3>
<p>No-one prepares you for the world after university. I applied for some internships and was offered a placement at a big studio firm in London, but it was unpaid. University had a funding scheme where they offered me a grant, workshop space and office that enabled me to set up on my own. I started out by making, exhibiting and selling my own wooden designs and lighting fixtures, working with local manufactures in Sheffield. It was very much trial and error as I didn’t know much at all about running a business. I just knew I wanted to be designing. I then worked different places, and eventually started working part time for Sir Terence Conran, which gave me a foothold in the industry and things moved from there.</p>
<p><em> </em></p>
<div style="text-align: center;"><a href="https://menuspace.com/products/ray-table-lamp-portable"><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0262/3959/8658/files/GS_3_1024x1024.jpg?v=1658304299" alt="" style="float: none;"></a></div>
<h3></h3>
<h3>How you approach your work?</h3>
<p>My starting point is always pen and paper: I sketch. From the perspective of a brief, or a gap in the market, a material, or to solve a problem. Often, I’ll come up with an idea that I think is viable; it’s a nice moment when I think I’ve got something. From there I create and refine prototypes in cardboard and wood.</p>
<p><em> </em></p>
<h3>Who or what has been most influential to your creativity and how? </h3>
<p>A while back I was given a stack of Designs of the Year books from the 1980s to mid-00s. They’re not published any longer, but it’s interesting to see what has aged well and what has simply disappeared from the design radar. Simple designs seem to fare best over time.</p>
<p><em> </em></p>
<div style="text-align: center;"><a href="https://menuspace.com/products/ray-table-lamp-portable" target="_blank" title="MENU Ray Table Lamp, Portable by Daniel Schofield" rel="noopener noreferrer"><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0262/3959/8658/files/GS_4_1024x1024.jpg?v=1658304348" alt="" style="float: none;"></a></div>
<h3></h3>
<h3>What is your design philosophy?</h3>
<p>I like things to be simple. I think there is a real beauty in that: when it’s all it needs to be. Especially with the world today. We’re living in an age of excess. Design for me should be simple and comprehensible but also with an element of surprise – whether that’s a material or a design feature, a function or a story behind the piece. I try to avoid trends and instead work to solve problems while refining everything down to its essence – with a hint of added charm.</p>
<p> </p>
<h3>Describe the process of creating the Ray Table Lamp. What influenced the style of it and what challenges did you face during the design process?</h3>
<p>Ray was created in the first lockdown of 2020. I had time to think of new designs and thought about the interesting typology of <a href="https://menuspace.com/collections/portable-table-lamps" title="Portable lamps">portable lights</a>. My granddad was a miner and we had miniature commemorative miners lamps at home. They were a good reference of what a portable light needs to be. I looked to their forms, simplifying them as much as possible. It made sense to me to be able to take the entire lamp apart, to change the battery or the bulb or repair if damaged. It was also essential to be waterproof, allowing for use outside as well as indoors. I wanted Ray to be robust, with thick powder-coated metal and the sensation of being a tool yet domestic at the same time.</p>
<p><em> </em></p>
<div style="text-align: center;"><a href="https://menuspace.com/products/ray-table-lamp-portable" title="MENU Ray Table Lamp, Portable by Daniel Schofield"><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0262/3959/8658/files/GS_5_1024x1024.jpg?v=1658304406" alt="" style="float: none;"></a></div>
<h3></h3>
<h3>What’s the story behind its name?</h3>
<p>Naming a product is always really hard. The name Ray is an abbreviation of my granddad’s name, Raymond. But it also alludes to the ray of light the lamp emits. That was a nice moment, thinking of the name.</p>
<p> </p>
<h3>What makes a design great? </h3>
<p>For me, it’s a balance between integrating seamlessly in a room but feeling well designed, well thought out and well-made when you interact with it. The world is hyper visual right now, which frustrates me because I think people can forget what design should actually be doing: making people’s lives better. Whether that’s end user, the people making it, its end-of-life impact on the environment, there’s a long chain of obligations and ethics that should be considered along the way.</p>
<p> </p>
<h3>What excites you as a designer?</h3>
<p>I’m most comfortable working with wood but like to explore new materials and processes. That’s exciting. I also like the challenge of designing a chair with its many angles and archetypal form, as well as fusion of comfort and function – something that feels familiar yet special. I’d love to design and build my own house. It would be simple; a lot of wood and greenery, and some bricks.</p>
<p> </p>
<div style="text-align: center;"><a href="https://menuspace.com/products/ray-table-lamp-portable" target="_blank" title="MENU Ray Table Lamp, Portable by Daniel Schofield" rel="noopener noreferrer"><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0262/3959/8658/files/GS_6_1024x1024.jpg?v=1658304246" alt="" style="float: none;"></a></div>
<h3></h3>
<h3>How can we futureproof our planet through design?</h3>
<p>It’s a conundrum. I don’t think a lot of people think about these things, although it is changing slowly. The average consumer just sees a nice chair, for example. However, I do think we are seeing a more ethical brand-based mentality filter through. And at the end of the day, it doesn’t really matter if the consumer notices. It’s a designer’s responsibility to ensure a product is sustainable on all fronts. It’s a never-ending journey to make something reparable. We’re limited in part by technology and the evolution of design. The fun challenge is how we can make things better. There’s always room for improvement. Should we just stop making things? Sometimes I think that the best thing we can do for the environment is to stop designing more, but there will always be an appetite for the next thing, or a new technology will come along and change everything. You just have to keep pushing forward.</p>
<h2><a href="https://menuspace.com/products/ray-table-lamp-portable">Explore the Ray Table Lamp here.</a></h2>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://audocph.com/blogs/news/ib-kofod-larsen</id>
    <published>2022-06-24T15:09:35+02:00</published>
    <updated>2023-12-21T08:42:48+01:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://audocph.com/blogs/news/ib-kofod-larsen"/>
    <title>Ib Kofod-Larsen</title>
    <author>
      <name>Audo Copenhagen</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<h2>Modern-day design afficionados now have the chance to acquire an exceptional piece of Danish design history as Audo puts The Penguin Chair by Ib Kofod-Larsen into production.</h2>
<div style="padding: 56.25% 0 0 0; position: relative;"><iframe title="Ib Kofod-Larsen Low Version" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%;" src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/816892936?badge=0&amp;autopause=0&amp;player_id=0&amp;app_id=58479" allowfullscreen="" allow="autoplay; fullscreen; picture-in-picture" frameborder="0"></iframe></div>
<script src="https://player.vimeo.com/api/player.js"></script>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
<p>Ib Kofod-Larsen is the epitome of Danish Modern. His furniture creations sit in the tension field between art and design. Although they have clear references to the mid-century period, they proffer a contemporary aesthetic that makes it difficult to decode whether they were designed then or now. Defined by a simplicity and straightforwardness that belies their complex craft and thoughtful details, Kofod-Larsen’s elegant designs are rare examples of Danish furniture at its finest.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><span>B</span>orn in Denmark on 6 May 1921, Kofod-Larsen excelled as a carpenter’s apprentice, graduating top of his class in 1944 before going on to study architecture at Denmark’s prestigious Royal Danish Academy of Fine Arts. As well as drawing houses, banks and schools, he also sketched furniture, glassware, silver and textiles. The prolific designer even turned his hand to designing televisions and radios. His body of work was lauded around the world and exhibited in cities from Copenhagen and Milan to New York and Chicago. After his death at 82 in 2003, his children discovered a vast archive of design sketches and prototypes. </p>
<p> </p>
<p><img alt="" src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0262/3959/8658/files/ib-kofod-larsen-journal-image-1_1024x1024.jpg?v=1656326891"></p>
<p> </p>
<script src="https://player.vimeo.com/api/player.js"></script>
<h3></h3>
<p>A private man, Kofod-Larsen shunned publicity, living out his motto, “he who lives hidden, lives well,” and thus he stood in the shadows of many of his peers. Yet his legacy lives on through some of the spectacular designs he created over the course of his notable career. One such piece is The Penguin Chair.</p>
<p>Imagined by Ib Kofod-Larsen in 1953, the signature design was first launched in the US where it received rave reviews. Echoing the aesthetics of the great American Modernists of the period, its slightly oversize proportions – a generous seat and back, the latter with integrated, flipper-like armrests – and contrasting slender metal frame ensured the sophisticated chair was anything but ordinary. A designer for the people, Kofod-Larsen’s infused his rudimentary ethos of comfort-meets-function into the Penguin; the embracing shell, upholstered seat and slanted frame offer support as the user sits. Similarly, the versioning of the chair in three different iterations – dining, lounge and rocking – brings its simple beauty to a new generation and ensures it fits a wide range of modern spaces and needs.</p>
<p> </p>
<h3><a href="https://audocph.com/pages/icons-collection">Explore Icons here</a></h3>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://audocph.com/blogs/news/truly-human-design</id>
    <published>2022-04-22T11:13:27+02:00</published>
    <updated>2023-12-27T11:57:08+01:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://audocph.com/blogs/news/truly-human-design"/>
    <title>Truly Human Design</title>
    <author>
      <name>Audo Copenhagen</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<h2>Today the term ‘craftsmanship’ is at the heart of conversations worldwide about design. While sustainability was and is a rising concern for designers and design customers, craftsmanship is a natural extension of this trend. It takes us back in time and into the future - and deep discussions of process.</h2>
<p style="text-align: left;"><img style="float: none;" src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0262/3959/8658/files/GT_1_1024x1024.jpg?v=1650546646"></p>
<h3></h3>
<h3>Why, in particular, are today’s leading designers determined to discuss craft, artisanship and the human hands that make the objects we love? Why now?</h3>
<p><br>“We assume everything around us is machine made,” says Gabriel Tan, the Portugal-based designer behind Audo’s collection of Aer Vases. “It’s simply not true.” <br><br>Tan is highlighting craftsmanship within his own studio practice and more broadly through the platform that international success he has awarded him, working in collaborations with Audo and Wallpaper*, to name a few.<br><br>“Craftsmanship brings attention to the question of consumption. We feel more connected to the person who made the object. It adds real value,” says Tan.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><img style="float: none;" alt="" src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0262/3959/8658/files/GT_2_BW_1024x1024.jpg?v=1650967726"></p>
<div style="text-align: left;"></div>
<p>A design is just an idea, a vision, and in many ways, a hope until it takes physical form. The physical effort behind the creation means everything. To stand strong, a design must be translated from the designer to experts of physical creation. It must be entrusted to experts of physical detail and skill. If all those involved are experienced and truly committed to the task, even a challenging design can be born true to the designer’s vision and intent.</p>
<p>It’s no wonder, perhaps, that designers - now celebrated internationally more than ever before - are asking brands and customers to consider craft. Without experts in the physical laws of strength, balance, flexibility and power, a design remains a dream.</p>
<p> </p>
<p style="text-align: start;"><img style="float: none;" alt="" src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0262/3959/8658/files/GT_3_1024x1024.jpg?v=1650547442"></p>
<h3></h3>
<h3>The designer’s relationship to craftsmanship is intrinsic</h3>
<p>Tan was inspired by icons like Alvar Aalto’s vases from 1930 when embarking on the design process for the Aer Vase Collection but his goal was to create something entirely new, drawing on the spirit of glass design and glass tradition. In partnership, Tan’s studio and Audo merged digital technology and traditional handcraft for the <a href="https://menuspace.com/collections/aer-collection">Aer Collection</a>, for a process that honors craftsmanship and technology with quality as its top value.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><img style="float: none;" alt="" src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0262/3959/8658/files/GT_4_BW_1024x1024.jpg?v=1650967813"></p>
<p><br>Tan’s vision for the Aer Vase was a tall, slim but remarkably stable glass vessel. The unique proportions presented a challenge; the height of <a title="Designer vases" href="https://menuspace.com/collections/vases">the vase design</a> requires the base to be heavy but delicate. Glass is a notoriously difficult material to shape and balance in strong, organic shapes. The base had to be perfect for the vase to stand strong. The thickness has to be exact.</p>
<p style="text-align: start;"><img style="float: none;" alt="" src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0262/3959/8658/files/GT_5_1024x1024.jpg?v=1650547527"></p>
<p><br>A mould was produced digitally for casting, and individual artisans blow glass into the mould for every vase and bowl, careful to extend the material in the mould properly using only the force of their breath. The physical effort of the artisan determines the glass’ thickness; if it is too thin and the vase will break, too thick and the piece diverges from the design. It’s this human effort - this craftsmanship - that makes each vase and bowl somewhat unique. It’s this process of production that connects the designer whose hands drew the design, to the artisans whose hands hold the tools tightly as they blow the glass, to the hands of the customer who will move the vase in their private space and carefully arrange flowers within it. <br><br>Craftsmanship makes the design human and is the essential bridge between designers and customers.<br><br>Needless to say, Audo is very pleased to see craftsmanship’s relevancy growing worldwide and to work with talented artisans and designers every day.</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://audocph.com/blogs/news/mentze-ottenstein-rosholm</id>
    <published>2022-02-15T15:28:39+01:00</published>
    <updated>2023-12-27T11:57:07+01:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://audocph.com/blogs/news/mentze-ottenstein-rosholm"/>
    <title>Wrapped in Comfort</title>
    <author>
      <name>Audo Copenhagen</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>Mathias Mentze, Alexander Ottenstein and Marie-Louise Rosholm share their thoughts on their collaboration on the Cocoon Textile Collection, made exclusively for Audo.</p><p><a class="read-more" href="https://audocph.com/blogs/news/mentze-ottenstein-rosholm">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<h2>Mathias Mentze, Alexander Ottenstein and Marie-Louise Rosholm share their thoughts on their collaboration on the Cocoon Textile Collection, made exclusively for Audo. </h2>
<p><img alt="" src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0262/3959/8658/files/MOR_01_1024x1024.jpg?v=1634672654"></p>
<h3>Tell us about your practice? </h3>
<p>Mathias Mentze: “We design interiors and furniture within an architectural context, and from an increasing awareness of and need for intimate, haptic and textural experiences. We want to revitalise the interior design field with a focus on well-being.”</p>
<p>Alexander Ottenstein: “I am a trained architect and for five years prior to joining Mathias in the company, I worked at two of the larger Danish architectural studios. This has made me familiar with large-scale projects, but it’s on the smaller projects, the kinds of assignments that we are doing now, that I feel my sensibilities and interests are being used to their full potential.”</p>
<p>Marie-Louise Rosholm: “As a textile designer I include as much sustainable matter as possible in my work. It’s vital to instil sustainability in every task and to discuss the topic in all collaborations. I have chosen to use my professional capabilities to fight for a better world.” </p>
<p><a href="https://audocph.com/products/losaria-pillow"><img alt="" src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0262/3959/8658/files/MOR_02_1024x1024.jpg?v=1634672682"></a></p>
<h3>How do you approach your work?</h3>
<p>Mathias Mentze: “Our approach is curious, site-specific and quite archaeological—we focus on unfolding local history, narratives and identities through design. We see interior design as a process of layering, with respect for what is – or was – already there. We are also fascinated by traditions and evolution, and work in close dialogue with trained craftspeople who deeply understand materials.” </p>
<p>Alexander Ottenstein: “Mathias is really good at ideating—coming up with some obscure reference he saw in a book ten years ago. While I am more, “Okay, so if this is what we want to achieve, how do we get there?” Both approaches are important in the creative process.”</p>
<p>Marie-Lousie Rosholm: “I’m a trained weaver and this practical approach is one of my most important skills, for many reasons. It also allows me to talk to production specialists to achieve results closer to the original idea than would otherwise be possible. Designing is about solving challenges on many different levels.”</p>
<p><img alt="" src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0262/3959/8658/files/MOR_03_1024x1024.jpg?v=1634672718"></p>
<h3>Which designers or creative movements have been most influential to your work?<em> </em>
</h3>
<p>Alexander Ottenstein: “Right now, what interests me the most is architecture and design from the Danish Arts and Crafts movement, Skønvirke, meaning ‘beautiful work.’ This era, just before Modernism, had an intense focus on craft and ornamentation but without being over-decorative.</p>
<h3>What makes a design valuable?</h3>
<p>Marie-Lousie Rosholm: “When is made to last aesthetically, sustainably and qualitively. That it fits the context and the economic climate it is made for. Also, when it has a purpose that is not only to make money.”</p>
<p><a href="https://audocph.com/products/losaria-pillow"><img alt="" src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0262/3959/8658/files/MOR_04_1024x1024.jpg?v=1634672742"></a></p>
<h3>How have you collaborated on this collection? What different skills and ideas did each of you bring to the project?</h3>
<p>Mathias Mentze: “Alex and I love the architectural qualities of textiles and we discovered so much in Marie-Louise’s extensive material archive. We spent six months examining the different ways of weaving certain fibres and discussing the personal narratives of the pieces in her collection. We then elaborated on these re-discoveries together.”</p>
<p>Alexander Ottenstein: “The process has been incredibly intuitive and inspiring. Mathias and I had never worked directly with textiles before, so we had long sessions with Marie-Louise at her studio, browsing her archives, working on the loom, discussing references to old <a title="Modern home textiles" href="https://menuspace.com/collections/rugs-home-textiles">Scand</a><a href="https://audocph.com/collections/rugs-home-textiles" title="Modern home textiles">inav</a><a title="Modern home textiles" href="https://menuspace.com/collections/rugs-home-textiles">ian textiles</a>, and sharing Proustian moments where an entire holiday is recalled through the memory of a simple French bistro napkin.” </p>
<p>Marie-Lousie Rosholm: “It’s been a homogeneous process with common references and values, energy, enthusiasm and healthy discussions which brought new aspects to the designs. And entirely without disagreement. I contributed with the materials and Mathias and Alexander with the designs, in one collaborative flow.”</p>
<h3>What were some of the main inspirations for the collection?</h3>
<p>Mathias Mentze: “We were aiming to work as sustainably as possible, using locally sourced mono-materials. We also wanted to create what we felt was missing from our own lives—textiles that are exclusive yet approachable and that will last.”</p>
<p>Alexander Ottenstein: “We wanted to create the kinds of products that we simply have not been able to find anywhere in the world. A lot of the collection sprung from this idea of the French bistro napkin.”</p>
<p><img alt="" src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0262/3959/8658/files/MOR_05_1024x1024.jpg?v=1634672770"></p>
<h3>How would you describe the Cocoon Collection and its materiality?</h3>
<p>Mathias Mentze: “We chose luxurious, natural, raw materials and added small details to create an intimate sense of scale and touch. We’ve combined different textiles—such as wool and silk—to create contrast and interest and to accentuate the natural drape of each piece.”</p>
<p>Alexander Ottenstein: “The result is both highly technical and beautiful. We wanted to create textiles that are ornamental not through prints or patterns, but through the inherent qualities of the material. There’s something incredibly authentic about the final products. They invite to touch and closer inspection: from the orange sheen of the red linen cushion to the way in which the stripes of the Battus Throw appear just by weaving in a few threads of silk.”</p>
<p>Marie-Lousie Rosholm: “The pieces in the collection are classic with a twist, and they push boundaries. Materiality has been our benchmark. I proposed mono materials to sustain the circularity of the products. It’s a collection of extraordinary Italian textiles; in fact, some of the pieces are the very pinnacle of Italian textile making.”</p>
<p><img alt="" src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0262/3959/8658/files/MOR_06_9e3ff858-a0f4-4a27-8dfe-0b5fa61e45d6_1024x1024.jpg?v=1634672861"></p>
<h3>How have you approached responsible design, sourcing and production?</h3>
<p>Marie-Lousie Rosholm: “I wanted to use local European suppliers and focus on mono materials for a simple recycling process. By using cellulosic materials sewn with cotton thread and labels, the entire cushion – bar the metal zip – is fully recyclable. Inner cushions are made from recycled PET bottles. Both material and production process are transparent and traceable. Most of all, our focus has been on longevity in terms of design, colours and materials. Longevity is the most sustainable action we can take.”</p>
<p><a href="https://audocph.com/collections/cocoon-collection">Explore the collection here.</a></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://audocph.com/blogs/news/ishinomaki-laboratory-expanding-the-world-of-diy</id>
    <published>2021-09-29T11:30:00+02:00</published>
    <updated>2023-12-21T08:42:48+01:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://audocph.com/blogs/news/ishinomaki-laboratory-expanding-the-world-of-diy"/>
    <title>Ishinomaki Laboratory: Expanding the World of DIY</title>
    <author>
      <name>Audo Copenhagen</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<h2>What started in 2011 as a public workshop initiative to provide the local community in Ishinomaki, Japan with simple, DIY furniture and crafting skills in the aftermath of a devastating earthquake has since turned into a global laboratory for creative design.</h2>
<p><img alt="" src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0262/3959/8658/files/Ishinomaki_1_1024x1024.jpg?v=1632875086"></p>
<p>“While volunteering in post-disaster Ishinomaki, I came across a local store owner who was repairing his shop himself with DIY methods. When I saw that, I became inspired and felt that a public workshop space in the town might be helpful and aid recovery efforts,” says Keiji Ashizawa, founder of Ishinomaki Laboratory.</p>
<p> <img alt="" src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0262/3959/8658/files/Ishinomaki_2_1024x1024.jpg?v=1632875125"></p>
<p>Partnering with local makers and materials under their Made in Local initiative, Ishinomaki Laboratory pushes the boundaries of do-it-yourself to empower communities around the world through design. Here, the brand’s products and legacy are put into a local context. Applying home-grown skills and materials from select international makers, Made in Local creates products that think outside of the box while building strong, local relationships.</p>
<p> <img alt="" src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0262/3959/8658/files/Ishinomaki_3_1024x1024.jpg?v=1632875152"></p>
<p>“In the beginning, volunteers in the community who endeavored to start their own businesses influenced and spurred each other on – and definitely inspired our origins with their creative energy. I believe that Ishinomaki Laboratory is now more than just a brand which originated in a disaster-stricken area: it has become a model for small, local brands and ventures contributing to regional revitalisation. And now, through the Made in Local initiative, we can share with our partners around the world the significance, the uniqueness and even the fun of Made in Local, as well as the various lessons that can be drawn from our story,” Ashizawa adds.</p>
<p> <img alt="" src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0262/3959/8658/files/Ishinomaki_4_1024x1024.jpg?v=1632875176"></p>
<p>Joining forces with Audo to produce products made in Denmark from resident materials and crafting skills, the Japanese label is a driving force in shaping the future of empowering design. Expanding the world of DIY and its potential, simple, functional and striking products are made using available machinery and resources, underpinning the original spirit of do-it-yourself. As Ashizawa notes, “Ishinomaki Laboratory’s furniture is for everyone and everyday life.” </p>
<p> <img alt="" src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0262/3959/8658/files/Ishinomaki_5_1024x1024.jpg?v=1632875202"></p>
<p>With a common mission to connect over good design and honest materials, Audo and Ishinomaki Laboratory present the <a href="https://audocph.com/products/ishinomaki-aa-stool">AA STOOL</a>, designed by TORAFU ARCHITECTS and the first in a series of DIY products. Produced in Denmark from local wood, the exposed screws, dimensional lumber and handcrafted look highlight just how innovative simplicity can be. Crafted from Danish Douglas fir and named after the shape of its profile, the flat pack <a title="Minimalistic DIY stool" href="https://menuspace.com/collections/bar-stools-counter-chairs">stool </a>has an untreated finish, customisable to the desired expression and which will patinate beautifully over time. Each pack of two stools is offered in two sizes – medium or tall – which can be used individually or in combination to create a wider seat. </p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://audocph.com/blogs/news/a-modernist-marriage</id>
    <published>2021-09-14T10:18:15+02:00</published>
    <updated>2024-05-04T03:58:35+02:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://audocph.com/blogs/news/a-modernist-marriage"/>
    <title>Anderssen &amp; Voll: A Modernist Marriage</title>
    <author>
      <name>Audo Copenhagen</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[<em>Working from their studio in Oslo, they make objects of beauty and relevance, looking to imbue a contemporary cultural expression into each piece while ensuring it is made to transcend shifting trends.<span> </span></em><p><a class="read-more" href="https://audocph.com/blogs/news/a-modernist-marriage">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<h2>Anderssen &amp; Voll are Norwegian designers Torbjørn Anderssen and Espen Voll. Working from their studio in Oslo, they make objects of beauty and relevance, looking to imbue a contemporary cultural expression into each piece while ensuring it is made to transcend shifting trends. Having collaborated with brands across the world for more than 20 years, they join forces with Audo on Brasilia, a <a title="Modern lounge chairs" href="https://menuspace.com/collections/lounge-chairs">new hybrid lounge chair</a> with fiery South American soul and sleek Scandinavian sensibilities.</h2>
<p style="text-align: left;"><img style="float: none;" alt="" src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0262/3959/8658/files/AW_1_1024x1024.jpg?v=1631572915"></p>
<h3>When did you first develop an interest in design?</h3>
<p><strong>Torbjørn</strong>: First after attending design school in Bergen. I originally decided to become a designer due to the tangible aspect of the profession – your work and effort in a physical form. The more you focus on something, the more interesting it becomes.</p>
<p><strong>Espen</strong>: For me it happened in childhood, growing up among classic design pieces. Making objects and drawing were my main interests as a child. I started out studying architecture, but its complexity never really appealed to me and I often ended up working on the details and the furniture.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><a href="https://audocph.com/products/brasilia-lounge-chair-sheepskin"><img style="float: none;" alt="" src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0262/3959/8658/files/AW_5_1024x1024.jpg?v=1631572964"></a></p>
<h3>Who has been most influential to your creativity and how?</h3>
<p><strong>Torbjørn</strong>: I remember a visit to Moss Gallery in New York City, January 2003. A reasonably priced chair from Magis was placed next to super exclusive Meissen porcelain. It instantly made me aware of the importance and power of beauty in a product.</p>
<p><strong>Espen</strong>: Meeting likeminded students at art school had a significant impact on my drive. Someone once said, ’Inspiration is for amateurs’ – you have to put in the hard work to make things happen. At school, we brought to life some great and inspiring projects both within and beyond the curriculum. Work brings ideas to life.</p>
<h3>Tell us about your practice and how you approach your work. </h3>
<p><strong>Torbjørn</strong>: Lots of talking over coffee, pen to paper, computer modelling and a mix of 3D printing and elaborate models we create in the studio. We build and refine every item to scale.</p>
<p><img alt="" src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0262/3959/8658/files/AW_3_1024x1024.jpg?v=1631573104"></p>
<h3>What is your signature design philosophy?</h3>
<p><strong>Torbjørn</strong>: We don’t really have a specific philosophy, but hope our values and preferences are present in our work. We try to not be tethered by this; there is a certain freedom in believing in your own freedom.</p>
<h3>How would you describe yourselves as designers?</h3>
<p><strong>Espen</strong>: Torbjørn looks to the semantics of an object and I to the overall harmony and detailing. We very rarely agree on anything initially. Our way of working is an ongoing debate, sometimes tantamount to quarrelling. We bring different things to the process and then knead our initial ideas into something else. It works for us. Or we wouldn’t be working together!</p>
<p><a href="https://audocph.com/products/brasilia-lounge-chair"><img alt="" src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0262/3959/8658/files/AW_8_1024x1024.jpg?v=1631573133"></a></p>
<h3>What informs your work?</h3>
<p><strong>Torbjørn</strong>: We’ve found that the most important part of a process is actually getting started. Once in it, anything can be inspirational. If you are designing a blanket, for instance, a texture on a wall, the front of a building or a detail on the clothes of a passer-by could all inform the design. If you weren’t in the process of designing a blanket, you probably wouldn’t recognise that texture or detail as important at all, having no conscious memory of it. We never wait for inspiration. If you want to make soup, it’s probably a good idea to fry some onions – or at the very least put some water in your pot. Staring out of the window will not make your soup.</p>
<p><img alt="" src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0262/3959/8658/files/AW_4_1024x1024.jpg?v=1631573171"></p>
<h3>What’s the best part of your job?</h3>
<p><strong>Torbjørn</strong>: When life was more stressful I used to answer: ‘The moment we get a new assignment and the moment we finish it in a good way.’ Now we take it easier, the best part of the job is probably having a coffee at the studio and talking to Espen about which direction to take a new project in. Visiting our colleagues in Italy or Copenhagen is also a favourite that has got even better since Covid-19 restrictions have lifted. It’s a great feeling to visit the factories where our designs form the basis of someone else’s working day. It’s wonderful to visit someone’s home and accidentally discover that something we’ve made has become a relevant and often cherished part of that person’s everyday life.</p>
<p><strong>Espen</strong>: The best part is the creation process. Imagine being able to daily create something that never has existed before? Being part of a great team at the office is also very rewarding.</p>
<h3>How long did it take to develop Brasilia?</h3>
<p><strong>Torbjørn</strong>: We started in autumn 2019 and worked through the pandemic. Our work is very much workshop-based so refining our design in 1:1 models in our studio really sped its development. The design was directly inspired by the mood at <a href="https://audocph.com/pages/audo-house">Audo House</a>. There was something about the setting – wooden sculptures, calm ambience and welcoming colours – that made us think of more exotic variations of Modernism rather than our own familiar Scandinavian roots. In many ways, the <a href="https://audocph.com/collections/brasilia-lounge-chair-and-ottoman">Brasilia Lounge Chair</a> is not the design Audo originally asked for or the one we set out to make, but somewhere along the way, through sketching and modelling, we were all convinced it was exactly the right one.</p>
<p><a href="https://audocph.com/products/brasilia-lounge-chair"><img alt="" src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0262/3959/8658/files/AW_6_1024x1024.jpg?v=1631573201"></a></p>
<h3>What influenced the style of it – and what challenges did you face during the design process?</h3>
<p><strong>Espen</strong>: Brasilia is a marriage of Scandinavian and Brazilian Modernism. We started off by sketching the wooden base – the, in some way, irrational shift from the cylindrical legs at the front to the broad, wooden boards at the back frame the seat, giving the chair personality and a distinctive look. It was important to achieve just the right kind of looseness to the textile covering to properly convey the great comfort of this piece.</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://audocph.com/blogs/news/the-eclipse-desk-by-fred-rigby-studio</id>
    <published>2021-06-30T14:55:11+02:00</published>
    <updated>2024-05-04T03:58:35+02:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://audocph.com/blogs/news/the-eclipse-desk-by-fred-rigby-studio"/>
    <title>Fred Rigby on his Design Practice and The Eclipse Desk</title>
    <author>
      <name>Audo Copenhagen</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[<em>Drawing inspiration from nature and melding the old with the new, designer Fred Rigby creates thoughtful spaces and intriguing, bespoke pieces that consider the spaces we inhabit and the functions we demand from his London-based interior and furniture design studio.</em><p><a class="read-more" href="https://audocph.com/blogs/news/the-eclipse-desk-by-fred-rigby-studio">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<meta charset="utf-8">
<h2>Fred Rigby grew up in Dorset, between the rolling hills of the English countryside and the limestone headlands that continue to inspire his work as a designer. Since graduating from London’s Kingston University with a degree in product and furniture design, he has worked with a range of designers and artists, developing a knowledge of processes including fibreglass casting and CNC technologies while perfecting his own craft from his eponymous studio in London.</h2>
<p> <span> </span><img alt="" src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0262/3959/8658/files/FredRigby_1_2048x2048.jpg?v=1624350863"></p>
<p>Drawing inspiration from nature and melding the old with the new, designer Fred Rigby creates thoughtful spaces and intriguing, bespoke pieces that consider the spaces we inhabit and the functions we demand from his London-based interior and furniture design studio.</p>
<p>His <a title="Modern office desk" href="https://menuspace.com/products/the-eclipse-desk">Eclipse Desk</a> for Audo unites his design ethos with sculptural, organic forms reminiscent of the shapes of pebbles.</p>
<h3>What inspires your practice?</h3>
<p>I am most inspired in and by nature. Although, anything can spark my imagination, whether it’s something I see or simply playing with scraps of paper or sketching forms.</p>
<p> <a href="https://audocph.com/products/the-eclipse-desk"><img alt="" src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0262/3959/8658/files/FredRigby_5_2048x2048.jpg?v=1624350937"></a></p>
<h3>Describe your creative process.</h3>
<p>It starts with sketching – crude line drawings that develop into more detailed elevations and plans before becoming models and maquettes and, finally, full-scale prototypes.</p>
<h3>Who or what has been most influential to this?</h3>
<p>There are so many amazing contemporaries whose work I love. I am, however, most inspired by the concepts behind art and thinking about how this can influence work.</p>
<p> <img alt="" src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0262/3959/8658/files/FredRigby_4_2048x2048.jpg?v=1624350921"></p>
<h3>What do you always consider before beginning each new project?</h3>
<p>I always look to the end-user when developing an initial project brief. I think about how a design will be used, where it will be placed. Ultimately, the most important thing is how it will look and function in a space. Pairing the two is key.</p>
<h3>You have created<span> </span>The<span> </span>Eclipse Desk for Audo. Tell us about your thoughts behind the design.</h3>
<p>I found inspiration for the piece by looking to the shapes and forms of pebbles I collected on a beach. I wanted to create a design that wasn’t static, and one which was bold in colour yet tactile in form. <a href="https://audocph.com/products/the-eclipse-desk">The Eclipse Desk</a> is ambidextrous: it can stand in the middle of a room as a centrepiece or up against a wall as a more conventional piece of furniture. Its solid oak top and intriguing form draw the eye and invite to touch.</p>
<p> <a href="https://audocph.com/products/the-eclipse-desk"><img alt="" src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0262/3959/8658/files/FredRigby_3_2048x2048.jpg?v=1624350894"></a></p>
<h3>What challenges did you face when creating it?</h3>
<p>How to integrate the lid into the desktop so that the grain chases through the top. The Eclipse Desk has an in-built storage cylinder to stow cables – or anything else, for that matter – out of sight, leaving behind a beautiful, clutter-free sculptural object in an office or space commandeered as a <a title="Home office furniture" href="https://menuspace.com/collections/office-space">work-from-home station</a>.</p>
<h3>How do you want people to use the Eclipse Desk?</h3>
<p>The Eclipse Desk is sculptural, functional and tactile. I want people to feel inspired when they sit at it. To lean back and touch the curved edge; to find a calmness within to focus on work.</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://audocph.com/blogs/news/afteroom</id>
    <published>2021-02-23T14:27:21+01:00</published>
    <updated>2024-05-04T03:58:35+02:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://audocph.com/blogs/news/afteroom"/>
    <title>Afteroom: An Advocate of the Traces of Time</title>
    <author>
      <name>Audo Copenhagen</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[<meta charset="utf-8"><meta charset="utf-8">
<p>The award-winning design studio, which marries Hung-Ming’s tech-savvy background as an industrial designer with Chen-Yen’s intuitive and creative approach to aesthetics.</p><p><a class="read-more" href="https://audocph.com/blogs/news/afteroom">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<h2>We hope our designs are recognised for their sophisticated simplicity combined with functional elegance and that people will use our designs as practical, elegant objects that are a graceful accompaniment to life.</h2>
<p><img style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" alt="" src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0262/3959/8658/files/Afteroom_1_8db04b9b-b6b1-406b-8653-1e5171ea1516_2048x2048.jpg?v=1614085658"></p>
<p><strong>Partners in life as well as design, Hung-Ming Chen and Chen-Yen Wei relocated from their native Taiwan to Sweden in 2006, where Hung-Ming studied design at Konstfack in Stockholm. Their adventure turned out to be more permanent than first planned, and the couple have since settled in the Swedish capital where they have </strong><strong>established Afteroom, their award-winning design studio, which marries Hung-Ming’s tech-savvy background as an industrial designer working with 3D software with Chen-Yen’s intuitive and creative approach to aesthetics.</strong></p>
<h4>When did you first become interested in design?</h4>
<p>Hung-Ming: “My high school major was electrical engineering, but it didn’t take me too long to realise that I wasn’t cut out for it and quickly needed to find another profession before it was too late. Luckily, I discovered industrial design.” Chen-Yen: “I was a business college student with no passion for the subject, but really enjoyed fashion. After graduating, I took a sabbatical. During that time, I realised that being a designer was the hidden dream I’d been wishing for.”<strong><em> </em></strong></p>
<p><img alt="" src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0262/3959/8658/files/Afteroom_2_2048x2048.jpg?v=1614085357"></p>
<h5>Which aspects of your background and upbringing have shaped your design principles and philosophy?</h5>
<p>Hung- Ming: “I grew up in an industrial area where my parents ran a small factory. When I was little, I was fascinated by how things were made so I guess that environment influenced me a lot.”</p>
<p>Chen-Yen: “As a child I often travelled with my family, which I believe is a really natural way to open a child's eyes to the world. Although I grew up in a crowded city, my parents tried their best to put us in contact with nature. Since then, I’ve had an appreciation of beauty. I think my creative influences mostly come from nature and companionship with my parents.”</p>
<meta charset="utf-8">
<p><img alt="" src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0262/3959/8658/files/Afteroom_5_2048x2048.jpg?v=1614085434"></p>
<h5>How would you describe your design aesthetic?</h5>
<p>Elegant, thoughtful simplicity.</p>
<h5>Tell us a bit about your design process.</h5>
<p>Hung-Ming: “We start by discussing ideas, and I sketch them out and make 3D models. Chen-Yen takes charge of the overarching appearance, proportion and colours and selects which projects we bring to life. I’ve worked as an industrial and interior designer for such a long time and know how to operate CAD software and navigate the mass production process.</p>
<p>However, I easily get blinded, so Chen-Yen takes on the responsibility for the aesthetics.”</p>
<p><img alt="" src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0262/3959/8658/files/Afteroom_4_2048x2048.jpg?v=1614085404"></p>
<h5>How long does it take to design a product?</h5>
<p><strong><em> </em></strong>Once we’ve got ideas, we’d start to sketch them out and make 3D models. If a design is viable, we’ll make a full-scale prototype to try it out in real life. The whole process usually takes more than a year.<strong><em> </em></strong></p>
<h5>Where do you get your ideas from?</h5>
<p>We visit the Konstfack library quite often. There are lots of different kinds of books we use for reference; not design books per se. Sometimes a great idea can come from a picture or a painting. Our daughter also influences our work. Since having her, we’ve sadly come to realise that we won’t be around forever. But if we do our job as designers well, she’ll see and experience our creations long after we’re gone.</p>
<p>In a way, it feels like we’ll still be with her. Being parents has given us so much inspiration and makes us consider the human relationship between time and objects. Both of us love timeless things. The notion of placing memories, emotions and thoughtful simplicity in an object is really romantic.</p>
<meta charset="utf-8">
<p><img alt="" src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0262/3959/8658/files/Afteroom_6_2048x2048.jpg?v=1614085464"></p>
<h5>What is Afteroom’s rasion d’etre?</h5>
<p>The main idea behind Afteroom is to be an advocate of the traces of time. All our designs share the spirit of this thought. We simply want to create objects people won’t get tired of and will want to keep for generations to come.</p>
<h5>What is the most challenging aspect of your practice?</h5>
<p>Compromise.</p>
<h5>What makes it all worthwhile?</h5>
<p>Working at our own independent design studio allows us to research the subjects we’re most interested. Often, if we dig deep enough, we can always find a new direction to try something unexpected.<strong><em> </em></strong></p>
<p><img alt="" src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0262/3959/8658/files/Afteroom_3_2048x2048.jpg?v=1614085510"></p>
<h5></h5>
<h5>What do you want people to take away from your designs?</h5>
<p><strong><em> </em></strong>We hope our designs are recognised for their sophisticated simplicity combined with functional elegance and that people will use our designs as practical, elegant objects that are a graceful accompaniment to life.</p>
<p>Discover Afteroom's designs for Audo <a href="https://audocph.com/collections/afteroom">here</a>.</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://audocph.com/blogs/news/no-place-like-home</id>
    <published>2021-02-11T09:30:39+01:00</published>
    <updated>2023-12-27T11:57:07+01:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://audocph.com/blogs/news/no-place-like-home"/>
    <title>No Place Like Home</title>
    <author>
      <name>Audo Copenhagen</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[<h1>“When I design spaces, I want people to feel like they want to stay there all the time, to spend time there. That, to me, is the essence of a great room.”</h1><p><a class="read-more" href="https://audocph.com/blogs/news/no-place-like-home">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<h2>Andrew Trotter, the designer behind a number of stunning Italian homes – including the serenely simple Puglinese farmhouse, Masseria Moroseta, which embraces traditional techniques and modern proportions in equal measure – talks to us about creating spaces that feel like home and the future of indoor living in the era of a new pandemic.</h2>
<p><img alt="" src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0262/3959/8658/files/Andrew_Trotter_1_2048x2048.jpg?v=1612977076"></p>
<h5></h5>
<h3>What constitutes a great space?</h3>
<p>Often great spaces are not very homely and have a “wow factor” simply because of their size or grandeur. For me, there are many different things at play. A great space comes from being very photogenic; that “wow” feeling you when you walk into a space, to merely feeling comfortable. A great space is one that feels homely: simplicity, patina on the walls, <a title="Minimalist furniture for modern homes" href="https://menuspace.com/collections/furniture">furniture</a> that feels lived in. It’s more about the comfiness of it all, not about show.</p>
<h3>What kind of spaces are you attracted to?</h3>
<p>I love beautifully minimalist spaces like the Neuendorf House by John Pawson and Claudio Silvestrin, but I’m not sure I could live there full time. I visited Luis Barragán’s house in Mexico earlier this year. Despite its high ceilings and large, open spaces, it feels homely thanks to the choice of textiles and the use of wood and colour. It is simple yet full of character – and interesting objects add to the appeal. Spaces that combine the old with the new – ones filled knick-knacks and with piles of magazines and books – make a space. And a comfortable sofa is key.</p>
<p><img alt="" src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0262/3959/8658/files/Andrew_Trotter_2_2048x2048.jpg?v=1612977175"></p>
<h3>What’s the most important factor to consider when creating spaces?</h3>
<p>When I design spaces, I want people to feel like they want to stay there all the time, to spend time there. That, to me, is the essence of a great room.</p>
<h3>We talk a lot about simplicity and minimalism, often interchanging the two. What’s the difference?</h3>
<p>They are similar in some ways, but not in others. Minimalism to me is something that is very pure: smooth, flat walls; clean, hidden lightning; stark and strict aesthetics. Simplicity is more about using patinas – in the plaster, on the walls – and the old. In essence, simplicity is minimalism with a bit more love and warmth.</p>
<p><img alt="" src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0262/3959/8658/files/Andrew_Trotter_3_2048x2048.jpg?v=1612977268"></p>
<h3>Has your practice changed with the new world we find ourselves in? What becomes more or less important?</h3>
<p>Funnily enough, the coronavirus hasn’t affected our work greatly. We are being commissioned for more and more projects all the time and have taken on around eight assignments this year. Boutique hotels and holiday homes, as well as a few private projects. We are experiencing rising interest in out-of-city escapes, too, with individuals wanting to set up a holiday home a few hours’ drive from where they live.</p>
<p><img alt="" src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0262/3959/8658/files/Andrew_Trotter_4_2048x2048.jpg?v=1612977317"></p>
<h3>Is the pandemic a call to rethink the way we live and create our spaces?</h3>
<p>I think people are more aware of personal space. In Spain, where I live, people didn’t care much about homes prior to the pandemic, and were always eating out in restaurants and hardly ever entertaining at home. We are now forced to spend more time at home – alone, too. Our homes have become spaces to live in and enjoy rather than just vessel for sleep. We see this changing across the world. As well as an increased interest in interior design. </p>
<h3>Prior to the pandemic, the new luxury was considered to be time and the feeling of being at home. Do you think the pandemic is changing our perception of luxury now that we have more time and are spending much of it at home?</h3>
<p>My Openhouse project came from this [Trotter is cofounder and publisher of Openhouse Magazine, a global forum for creatives to open their private spaces to the public for cultural events. –ed.]. In the first few years of Instagram, everyone felt more connected with their telephone than with each other. By opening our house to the public, showcasing artworks and photography and gathering to enjoy food and conversation, we connected with individuals on another level. We are currently unable to connect in the same way during the pandemic, but we still have this idea of where our food comes from, we are more selective about the furniture we buy, choosing well and more carefully because we understand that the world is not going to be here forever.</p>
<meta charset="utf-8">
<p><img alt="" src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0262/3959/8658/files/Andrew_Trotter_5_2048x2048.jpg?v=1612977345"></p>
<h3>We all strive for human connection in one shape or another. How do you see this developing in the time of the pandemic and what implications does it have on the way we shape our homes?</h3>
<p>Most of the places I design are in Italy, Greece, Australia and the US – and are very open to the air. Bedrooms with outdoor patios, places to sit and relax, arrangements that facilitate togetherness, but also provide options to retreat alone. Those who have previously dreamed of owning holiday home are making good on that right now, fulfilling their desire for a second home outside of the city, to work from, to live in, to entertain in. We are also seeing a change in the way hotels are created, with a minimum of bedrooms. People don’t want big anymore; they want to be looked after. Areas that were previously very communal are now being made more intimate with separate spaces to connect in and retreat to.</p>
<p><img alt="" src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0262/3959/8658/files/Andrew_Trotter_6_2048x2048.jpg?v=1612977412"></p>
<h3>What can we learn from the world today?</h3>
<p>I think to live frugally. More than that, I think we will see that we are really going to become mindful of what we spend our money on, of the time we spend doing things and what, in fact, we choose to do with it. I think we will see much more care and consideration being spent on these things, make sure it’s exactly right.</p>
<p> </p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://audocph.com/blogs/news/audo-passage-collection</id>
    <published>2021-01-19T09:18:49+01:00</published>
    <updated>2024-05-04T03:58:36+02:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://audocph.com/blogs/news/audo-passage-collection"/>
    <title>Passage Collection by Krøyer-Sætter-Lassen</title>
    <author>
      <name>Audo Copenhagen</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>The versatility of the collection means it works in a multitude of settings; at home, at work, at play.</p><p><a class="read-more" href="https://audocph.com/blogs/news/audo-passage-collection">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<h2>Founded in 2016 by Mads Sætter-Lassen and Emil Krøyer, their honest approach to design results in logical, functional and sculptural objects that showcase their strong cultural understanding and Danish design heritage to bridge the gap between art and design.</h2>
<h3><em>Where did you get your inspiration for this design? </em></h3>
<p><a href="https://audocph.com/collections/passage-collection">The Passage Collection</a>, comprising a stool and a lounge table in FSC®-certified solid oak, is inspired by the Old Masters, with clear references to the Danish cabinetmaking tradition. At the same time, it was important to us to bring the design up to date. Looking to the world we live in today, we have made every piece in the collection flat-pack, ensuring efficient and easy handling at every step. Bringing a piece from the collection home should be easy and fun.</p>
<div style="text-align: left;"></div>
<h3><em>Describe the collection in up to five words.</em></h3>
<p>Clever. Flatpack. Classic yet contemporary.</p>
<p> <img alt="" src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0262/3959/8658/files/MENU_PassageStools_1024x1024.jpg?v=1609927828"></p>
<h3><em>How do you want your design to make people feel?</em></h3>
<p>We want it to generate feelings of creation and connection. The flat-pack, self-assembly design connects the owner to the piece, bringing a sense of satisfaction at having played a part in its creation – to become attached to it is some way. Passage is incredibly quick and easy to assemble. Beyond that, we want people to enjoy the warmth and quality of its solid wood construction.</p>
<h3><em>Tell us about the different functions of each piece. </em></h3>
<p>The <a href="https://audocph.com/products/passage-stool">Passage Stool</a> is a hardworking, versatile piece everyone should own. Although designed for seating – as a permanent fixture around a table or an extra seat for unexpected guests – it can also be used as a side table. Furthermore, it’s stackable and an infinite number can be loaded on top of each other.</p>
<p>The different sized <a href="https://audocph.com/products/passage-lounge-table">Passage Lounge Tables</a> can be gathered in clusters, connecting each piece to create one whole. This makes them ideal for larger spaces, private and commercial.</p>
<p> <img alt="" src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0262/3959/8658/files/MENU_PassageLounge2_fcd8c9d7-73b4-4b2f-9ac5-63fc540514be_1024x1024.jpg?v=1609927787"></p>
<h3><em>How can the collection evolve in the future?</em></h3>
<p>We are already working to expand the collection with <a title="Stools and chairs for counter and bar" href="https://menuspace.com/collections/bar-stools-counter-chairs">counter and bar stools</a> and, hopefully, dining tables and a chair.</p>
<h3><em>Where do you see your design working best?</em></h3>
<p>The versatility of the collection means it works in a multitude of settings; at home, at work, at play. The Passage Stool is so that it can be used in every room of the home – in the bathroom for little ones to reach the sink; in the hallway for putting on shoes; in the living room as a seat; or in the bedroom as a table or landing place for clothes. The possibilities are endless.</p>
<h3><em>Why did you select wood for this design? </em></h3>
<p>FSC®-certified solid wood is long-lasting, sustainable and aesthetically pleasing. The tactile feeling of wood was an important consideration for both finished products. It is also able to be flatpacked – a fundamental element of the two designs.</p>
<p><img alt="" src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0262/3959/8658/files/MENU_Passage_detail_1024x1024.jpg?v=1609927744"></p>
<p><strong><em>The Designer</em></strong></p>
<p>The Copenhagen-based design studio Krøyer-Sætter-Lassen creates furniture and interior objects for clients across the world. Founded in 2016 by Mads Sætter-Lassen and Emil Krøyer, their honest approach to design results in logical, functional and sculptural objects that showcase their strong cultural understanding and Danish design heritage to bridge the gap between art and design. Krøyer-Sætter Lassen began their collaboration at the Royal Danish Academy of Fine Arts, School of Design, where they have graduated with their BA and subsequently, an MA.</p>
<p>Their collaboration has grown from a give-and-take about art and design into the creation of existing projects. The duo recognizes their differences and strengths allowing them to approach their process from different character angles. Krøyer-Sætter Lassen engages each other to seek new materials and perspectives in order to work in a nicety way.</p>
<p>Krøyer and Sætter-Lassen's honest focus is revealed through their consideration of material properties and tectonic details. They prefer to make the conscious choice of turning a joint or assembly into a visible design asset instead of concealing it -keeping true to the industrial way.</p>
<p><img alt="" src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0262/3959/8658/files/Kroyer-Saetter-Lassen_Portrait_1_1024x1024.jpg?v=1609857927"></p>
<p> </p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://audocph.com/blogs/news/the-umanoff-collection</id>
    <published>2020-08-28T16:04:00+02:00</published>
    <updated>2023-12-27T11:57:07+01:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://audocph.com/blogs/news/the-umanoff-collection"/>
    <title>The Umanoff Collection</title>
    <author>
      <name>Audo Copenhagen</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[<h2><strong><em>Arthur Umanoff galvanised the Mid-century Modern movement with his streamlined objects that placed form after function.</em></strong></h2><p><a class="read-more" href="https://audocph.com/blogs/news/the-umanoff-collection">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<h2><strong>Arthur Umanoff galvanised the Mid-century Modern movement with his streamlined objects that placed form after function. As Audo launches a collection of his most iconic works, his daughter Wendy reminisces about her father’s design legacy.</strong></h2>
<p>Despite remaining relatively unknown outside of the design industry, Arthur Umanoff (1923–1985) is widely regarded by collectors as a prominent figure in America’s Mid-century Modern movement. Together with his peers, he redefined the traditional furniture designs of the period, stripping away ornamentation in favour of function in order to accommodate the growing need for versatile <a href="https://audocph.com/collections/all-products" title="Furniture design">designs for the home</a>.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><a href="https://audocph.com/pages/arthur-umanoff"><img style="float: none;" src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0262/3959/8658/files/Arthur-Umanoff_2048x2048.jpg?v=1598614930" alt=""></a></p>
<p>An artistic man from a lower-middle-class New York City family, out of high school Umanoff joined the American war effort and trained as a Navy medic, serving at a naval air station in New Jersey until the end of the war in 1945. Unsure of his calling, he went on to study design at the Pratt Institute in Brooklyn, New York before cutting his teeth as a designer-manufacturer in New York City.</p>
<p>“In those days it was not hard for a young designer interested in furniture or architecture to be familiar with the European design movement to simplify the home, inside and out,” recounts Wendy Umanoff, who is charged with safeguarding her father’s design legacy. “Ready to rebel against the worn-out furniture of their parents’ age, young American designers were powerfully influenced by the simpler, more organic forms of Danish masters such as Finn Juhl, Hans J. Wegner and Børge Mogensen.”</p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><a href="https://audocph.com/products/umanoff-wine-rack"><img style="float: none;" src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0262/3959/8658/files/MENU_Wine-Rack-_8_1024x1024.jpg?v=1598960175" alt=""></a></p>
<p>Thanks to his intelligent use of natural materials and predilection for function, Umanoff soon garnered attention for his work. Although he did not succeed as a furniture builder himself, his designs attracted manufacturers who were just learning how to sell a new way of thinking about furniture to a new generation of Americans. Using wrought iron, brass, birch and walnut veneers, jute roping and rattan, as well as tempered masonite and leather, Umanoff’s sculptural yet purposeful objects remain as relevant today in furniture designs and home accessories as they did in the mid-1900s.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><a href="https://audocph.com/products/umanoff-candle-holder"><img style="float: none;" src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0262/3959/8658/files/MENU_UmanoffCandleHolder_1024x1024.jpg?v=1598959677" alt=""></a></p>
<p>“The use of materials and the proportions of my father’s furniture in his early designs created a harmonious balance for modern home living. His early pieces were practical and utilitarian, less ornamental,” notes Wendy. In all his work, Umanoff refined tradition and reflected warmth, developing objects perfectly attuned to their primary purpose and both aspirational and attainable. </p>
<p>In the early 50s, Umanoff became life-long friends with other young creatives, including Ben Siebel, who also were catching the post-war wave in New York City and orbited around artists like Raymond Rocklin, Leo Amino and Milton Hebald, whose famous Zodiac sculptures greeted travellers at JFK Airport’s PanAm terminal for more than half a century. A charming, charismatic man socially connected to the design world and his local community, Umanoff was always willing to help others — especially if it involved any form of problem-solving regarding design.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><img style="float: none;" src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0262/3959/8658/files/MENU_Planters-_7_1024x1024.jpg?v=1598959737" alt=""></p>
<p>“[He] was a very hands-on designer, involved with every aspect of working through the design details during the manufacturing process. It was the way in which he worked through the fabrication details of his furniture collections with makers that delighted him and drove him to create more,” recounts Wendy, having witnessed first-hand her father’s passion and process on a working trip to Guatemala.</p>
<p>“He believed that it was at the time of actually producing a product or prototyping that offered opportunities for correcting production problems in real time. That stimulated him as much as it did when creating the early concept sketches of a specific design. It was clearly evident to me then that the working relationships my father made throughout his life energised his creative mind and spirit.”</p>
<p><a href="https://audocph.com/collections/arthur-umanoff">Explore the Arthur Umanoff Collection at Audo</a>.</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://audocph.com/blogs/news/plinth-story-cut-from-a-stone</id>
    <published>2020-08-28T14:51:00+02:00</published>
    <updated>2024-05-04T03:58:36+02:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://audocph.com/blogs/news/plinth-story-cut-from-a-stone"/>
    <title>Plinth – A Story Cut From Stone</title>
    <author>
      <name>Audo Copenhagen</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[<h2>Each piece of carefully selected marble is assembled by hand to ensure that the sides line up perfectly.</h2><p><a class="read-more" href="https://audocph.com/blogs/news/plinth-story-cut-from-a-stone">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<h2>Each piece of carefully selected marble is assembled by hand to ensure that the sides line up perfectly.</h2>
<p>A favoured medium of the Greeks and Romans in both architecture and art, marble has come to symbolise elegance and sophistication. <a href="https://audocph.com/collections/the-plinth-collection" title="Marble plinth">The Plinth</a> builds upon and subtly subverts that essence, using marble instead as a means to showcase other items, as well as standing as a sculptural item on its own. The Plinth is the result of what’s been cut away, revealing a core of quality and beauty. No piece of marble is alike; that’s because the detailing of each naturally occurring rock is created over time by nature, rendered in limestone or dolomite. The dashes of colour you see are called veins and they are most often made of silt, sand, clay, iron oxides or chert grains found within the original stone. While they may be called impurities in production jargon, it is these splashes of colour and texture that make marble so special. </p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
<div style="padding: 56.25% 0 0 0; position: relative;"><iframe title="Plinth Journal with Titles High Version" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%;" src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/816907373?h=7e4969a10a&amp;badge=0&amp;autopause=0&amp;player_id=0&amp;app_id=58479" allowfullscreen="" allow="autoplay; fullscreen; picture-in-picture" frameborder="0"></iframe></div>
<p> </p>
<p>Each piece of carefully selected marble is assembled by hand to ensure that the sides line up perfectly. The result is podiums that are consistent in shape and quality while unique in marbling pattern. The black marble, Nero Marquina, comes from the north of Spain, while the white marble, known as Carrara, as well as Calacatta Viola – off-white with striking purple veins – come from Italy. Brown grey marble, called Grey Kendzo, is from Iran. All share a low refraction index, so they allow light to penetrate a few millimetres into the surface before refracting, giving the Plinth its aura of vitality. By utilising simple shapes and the highest possible quality control, Audo allows the marble to speak for itself.</p>
<p><img alt="" src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0262/3959/8658/files/plinth_3_1024x1024.jpg?v=1599489998"></p>
<p><img alt="" src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0262/3959/8658/files/plinth_10_1024x1024.jpg?v=1599490040"></p>
<p><img alt="" src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0262/3959/8658/files/plinth_1024x1024.jpg?v=1599490057"></p>
<p><img alt="" src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0262/3959/8658/files/plinth_6_1024x1024.jpg?v=1599490095"></p>
<p><img alt="" src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0262/3959/8658/files/plinth_8_1024x1024.jpg?v=1599490127"></p>
<ol></ol>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://audocph.com/blogs/news/danielle-siggerud</id>
    <published>2020-06-25T15:08:00+02:00</published>
    <updated>2023-12-27T11:57:07+01:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://audocph.com/blogs/news/danielle-siggerud"/>
    <title>Danielle Siggerud</title>
    <author>
      <name>Audo Copenhagen</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>A sense of timelessness and tenderness inform the practice of Copenhagen-based Norwegian designer and architect Danielle Siggerud.</p><p><a class="read-more" href="https://audocph.com/blogs/news/danielle-siggerud">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<h3>A sense of timelessness and tenderness inform the practice of Copenhagen-based Norwegian designer and architect Danielle Siggerud. The Androgyne Side Table marked her first foray into product design, and the collection is now being expanded with the addition of a statement dining table and sofa table with the same characteristic lines and natural materials of its predecessor – conveying Audo's commitment to making beautiful objects in natural materials for everyday use with a simple, yet refined design language.</h3>
<p><img alt="" src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0262/3959/8658/files/MENU_DanielleSiggerud_3_1024x1024.jpg?v=1599489754"></p>
<h3>Describe your practice.</h3>
<p>To me, architecture and design are about eliminating excess to focus on essential forms. It’s about rigorous attention to detail and carefully selecting the right materials for the design we’re making which affords human interaction.</p>
<h3>What inspired you to create the table?</h3>
<p>The Androgyne Side Table was originally developed as a modern and versatile table for Audo, Audo’s former showroom café. I wanted to create a design with a simple silhouette characterised by the pure use of materials with a clear, refined silhouette that contrasted a solid line with a soft line. It balances both masculine and feminine strengths and, like its name suggests, is androgynous, which is the symbol of a whole and the definition of original harmony in Greek mythology. The new tables are a development of the original design and retain the same simple silhouette while introducing a new, natural materials, shapes and functions for daily settings.</p>
<p><img alt="" src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0262/3959/8658/files/MENU_DanielleSiggerud_1_1024x1024.jpg?v=1599489864"></p>
<h3>The original Androgyne table is crafted in steel. What made you select wood and marble for the new tables?</h3>
<p>The Androgyne Collection has always been about honouring perfectly executed joinery and celebrating natural materials. The use of rich, warm oak on the <a title="Modern dining tables" href="https://menuspace.com/collections/dining-tables">dining table</a> makes it easy to pair with any interior style, and the wood will age gracefully over time. Likewise, kunis breccia adds a new dimension to the collection on the <a title="Modern side and coffee tables" href="https://menuspace.com/collections/side-coffee-tables">sofa table</a>. Its refined, solid expression is offset with the blend of different stones in warm tones. The table’s flexible shape makes it a versatile piece of furniture in any space, as a lounge table or bench for books or decorations. It is about creating personal spaces dependent on the context, place and function it will be a part of.</p>
<p><img alt="" src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0262/3959/8658/files/MENU_DanielleSiggerud_2_1024x1024.jpg?v=1599489882"></p>
<h3>What kind of spaces do you see the collection in?</h3>
<p>It makes a simple statement about its versatility and multiple functions, which lends a timeless quality to the design. It equally complements both modern and antique, timeworn furniture, objects or spaces. I’ve always been attracted to contrasts and how different textures, materials or shapes collide as each fragment appears stronger as an individual, yet becoming whole together. I can see the dining table in a home space, as a natural gathering point that allows people to come together in different ways.</p>
<p><img alt="" src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0262/3959/8658/files/MENU_DanielleSiggerud_5_1024x1024.jpg?v=1599489901"></p>
<h3>What do you want people to take away from the collection?</h3>
<p>I hope they’ll notice how versatile it is and how it can be arranged with almost anything in an interior space and will stand the test of time. It’s always exciting to launch a new product. It signals the beginning of a new chapter for a design to evolve and grow with day-to-day living.</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
</feed>
