<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xml:lang="en" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/" xmlns:s="http://jadedpixel.com/-/spec/shopify">
  <id>https://audocph.com/blogs/news.atom</id>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://audocph.com/blogs/news"/>
  <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://audocph.com/blogs/news/tagged/audo-house.atom"/>
  <title>Audo Copenhagen - Connected Journal</title>
  <updated>2024-04-26T09:29:57+02:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Audo Copenhagen</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <id>https://audocph.com/blogs/news/in-conversation-with-fanny-bylund-1</id>
    <published>2023-06-06T13:08:35+02:00</published>
    <updated>2023-12-21T08:42:48+01:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://audocph.com/blogs/news/in-conversation-with-fanny-bylund-1"/>
    <title>In conversation with Fanny Bylund</title>
    <author>
      <name>Audo House</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<h3>We had the honor of sitting down with Fanny Bylund, the Swedish ceramic artist – read our interview to gain insight to Fanny's work and learn about the collection she exclusively created for the Audo House. </h3>
<p> </p>
<div style="text-align: center;"><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0262/3959/8658/files/Fanny_02_low.jpg?v=1686652389" alt=""></div>
<div style="text-align: start;"></div>
<div style="text-align: start;"></div>
<div></div>
<h3></h3>
<h3>Could you describe your creative background and how you came to work with sculptures and art in general? </h3>
<p><br>Growing up as an only child I entertained myself in my own creative world and that’s pretty much what I still do in my studio.<br>I have a bachelor’s degree in Medium and Material-based Art from Oslo National Academy of the Arts, specified in ceramics. Before that I went to a Swedish folk high school for two years, focusing on ceramic form. Clay is the material I work best in, it suits my tempo and my way of thinking. When I move, the clay moves - as the sculptor Tony Cragg once said. I love the possibility of both adding and taking away material.</p>
<p> </p>
<h3>Where do you draw inspiration from for art pieces?</h3>
<p><br>I draw a lot of inspiration from shapes I see in nature but also organic shapes I see in my daily urban life. Such as the fruit and vegetable section, or dry leaves on the ground. The sharp edges of the banana peel where the sides meet, or the round flat shape of a dried bean, for example.</p>
<p> </p>
<h3>In your own words what characterizes your artworks?</h3>
<p><br>When I’m making my sculptures I focus on rhythm, balance and contrasts. I see my work balancing somewhere in between architectural, strict forms and organic, soft shapes. I like both the minimalistic expression and the flowy organic expression. In my sculptures I try to explore how simple a form can be while still being interesting to me.</p>
<p><strong></strong> </p>
<div style="text-align: start;"><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0262/3959/8658/files/Fanny_05_low.jpg?v=1686652265" alt=""></div>
<p> </p>
<h3>What does your work process typically look like?</h3>
<p><br>It starts with a vague sketch. When I can’t imagine what something I’ve drawn would look like in 3D, I need to sculpt it. When I start building, I try to keep an open mind of how the clay behaves, trying to make room for the clay to speak as well. If the clay collapses in an interesting way, then I might try to emphasize that, instead of sticking to the sketch.<br> <br>I build my sculptures from bottom to top. The size of the base decides the size of the sculpture. The technique is called coiling, it's like I’m knitting my pieces with a thread in clay, and all sculptures are hollow. <br><br>In the building process it's a lot about timing. If I’m building too fast there is too much soft clay at once and the sculpture collapses. If I let it set for too long, the clay dries out and I can’t continue shaping it or adding new clay. When I'm building a sculpture I need to be totally present in the moment and alone in my studio, only having the radio on for some background murmur.</p>
<p> </p>
<h3>Lastly, which one is your favourite piece of this collection and why? </h3>
<p><br>To be honest, and maybe a bit cheesy, my favorite sculpture is always the one I'm building right now, or the next one to come. I'm never 100% satisfied, which I try to see as a good thing because it makes me want to do better next time. <br><br>But to answer the question better, I would say that for the moment, my favorite is the big, round, rather flat one - it takes up a lot of space but at the same time it doesn't. I have recently started experimenting with glaze details, just trying to see glaze as another kind of surface. I like the contrast between the matte, rough surface and the shiny, slippery one. An interesting combination for both the hand and the eye.</p>
<p> </p>
<div style="text-align: start;"><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0262/3959/8658/files/Untitled_design_6_1024x1024.png?v=1686048550" style="float: none;"></div>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://audocph.com/blogs/news/interview-with-slouv</id>
    <published>2023-06-06T11:42:28+02:00</published>
    <updated>2023-12-21T08:42:48+01:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://audocph.com/blogs/news/interview-with-slouv"/>
    <title>Interview with Slouv</title>
    <author>
      <name>Audo House</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<h3>We had the honor of sitting down with the Turkish art brand, Slouv and talk about the concept and inspiration behind the collection that they exclusively created for the Audo House.</h3>
<p> </p>
<div style="text-align: start;"><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0262/3959/8658/files/Untitled-3_1024x1024.jpg?v=1686050307" style="float: none;"></div>
<div></div>
<div style="text-align: start;"></div>
<div style="text-align: start;"></div>
<h3>Could you briefly introduce yourself and tell us about your work?<br><br>
</h3>
<p>I was born and raised in Turkey, and after a long educational journey, graduated as an industrial engineer. Throughout my life, I've always had a desire for creativity, transformation and production. I engaged in various jobs in different sectors during my education and also worked in manufacturing fields. After graduating, I took steps towards my true passion and pursued artistic creation. I created my own workshop and embarked on artistic production, which made me feel much more free and aware. The minimalization of my life allowed me to find tranquility and transform those moments into art.</p>
<p> </p>
<h3>Can you shed some light on how you paved your way as an artist and creator?<br><br>
</h3>
<p>To me, being creative is a way to shut out the pressures of the external world. I started painting to establish a deeper connection with both life and myself. Knowing that I will create something when I enter the studio is the most fulfilling feeling for me. I enjoy progressing on this path and witnessing my growth and transformation. While the outcome is important, I also focus on the process itself.</p>
<p> </p>
<h3>In your own words what characterizes your artworks?<br><br>
</h3>
<p>My artworks are characterized by strong, minimalist, natural forms, colors and shapes. Nature has always been my inspiration, and art is a sort of discovery and journey for me. Transferring my current emotions onto the canvas liberates me. I approach my drawings both spontaneously and consciously, purely based on instincts. I don't aim for flawless beauty, and I think the most important aspect is the moments when I create my paintings. It's a magical moment to express myself when I feel inadequate in conveying my emotions, a creative outlet I can resort to.</p>
<p><strong></strong> </p>
<div style="text-align: start;"><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0262/3959/8658/files/Untitled_design_5_1024x1024.png?v=1685712721" style="float: none;"></div>
<p> </p>
<h3>What inspired the collection that you showcase at the Audo House, 'Boden'?<br><br>
</h3>
<p>The collection I showcase at the Audo House, 'Boden,' is inspired by unexpected relationships that emerge between shapes. I created this series inspired by the beauty of different colors and forms. Examining natural beauty and minimal forms is the main theme of my works. Based on this, I created eight different paintings. </p>
<p> </p>
<h3>How does your creative work process typically look like?<strong></strong> <br><br>
</h3>
<p>In my creative work process, I mainly work with acrylics and compose my artworks on canvases. When forming a series, I start by combining different drawings I've collected over time. I do color experiments and make numerous sketches before I make the final selections. Finally, I combine them with a wooden frame, adding the final touch. Being organized and orderly is important for me, and it allows me to be more productive. Only in this way can I create the space for creativity.</p>
<p> </p>
<div style="text-align: start;"><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0262/3959/8658/files/Untitled_design_9a4a3bed-b93c-4817-a9b3-e59e3dc1b559_1024x1024.png?v=1685713487" style="float: none;"></div>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://audocph.com/blogs/news/featured-artist-sophie-klerk</id>
    <published>2021-11-23T17:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2023-12-21T08:41:59+01:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://audocph.com/blogs/news/featured-artist-sophie-klerk"/>
    <title>Featured Artist: Sophie Klerk</title>
    <author>
      <name>Audo House</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<h3 data-mce-fragment="1">Sophie Klerk is a Danish collage artist who is known for her intuitive approach to materiality and form. Having lived and worked in the Netherlands, England, Mexico and most recently in New Zealand, Sophie’s work is largely shaped by her international background. Her artistic style is often described as unique, minimalist and expressive and explores the interactions between different papers, colours, shades, textures, threads, paint and photos.</h3>
<p><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0600/3123/8322/files/me_working_1024x1024.jpg?v=1654095686" alt=""><br><br>Inspired by the curiosity and challenge of the unknown, Sophie’s stitched-together collages often bear the imprints of the previous lives of their materials. Her work is held in private collections worldwide, and she undertakes collaborations and commissions on request</p>
<div>
<br>
<h3>Could you tell us about how you came to be in your current career? <strong><br><br></strong>
</h3>
</div>
<p>I started my creative endeavours as a graphic designer, but after a few years, came to realize that I missed expressing my own personal take on the world. I decided to take some time off and began building a toolbox, equipped only with an old camera and my curiosity for the unknown. I started creating small collages using photographs, vintage books and things I found along the way. In other words, instead of illustrating other peoples’ stories — I began creating my own.<br><br>In my formative years, I told stories using photography and typography. As my work evolved, I’ve transitioned from graphics and imagery to working mainly with texture, colour and composition.<br><br><br></p>
<h3>How would you describe your artworks?<strong><br><br></strong>
</h3>
<p>I regard my work as a dialogue between myself and the material library I’ve accumulated over the years. I am endlessly fascinated by the interaction between different papers, colours, shades, textures and paints, and how they can come together to form new compositions and meanings.<br><br>My creative process is very intuitive, and through the process of creating an artwork, chaos turns into order and fragments become whole. My collages invite viewers to step inside my universe, while simultaneously discovering their own relationship to the artwork.<br><br></p>
<p><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0600/3123/8322/files/Journal_Template_1_2048x2048.png?v=1654095806"></p>
<h5></h5>
<h3>
<br>What inspires your work?<strong><br><br></strong>
</h3>
<p>Having lived in Mexico for 6 months, there is a distinct imprint of the people, the colours, the walls and layers of history that is present in my work. Moving to New Zealand was very inspirational and important for my creative process. While fully establishing myself as an artist there, it offered me a chance to see things with fresh eyes while immersing myself in my own universe.<br><br>When I reflect on what inspires me, I find myself revisiting the traces of places, feelings and memories within the fragments I collect. Inspiration, I find, often arrives in the most unexpected of places and moments.</p>
<h5></h5>
<p> </p>
<h3>Could you describe the process of how you create your artworks?<strong><br><br></strong>
</h3>
<p>I often work on several artworks at the same time. It can take hours, days or weeks before the final piece has found its place and the work has found a sense of balance. Searching for this harmony is essential but at the same time, there must be a sense of spontaneity in the process. When something is too careful or “perfect”, it doesn’t feel right, and I must remind myself to trust the process and embrace the uncertainty of creation</p>
<p><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0600/3123/8322/files/12_2048x2048.png?v=1654095887"></p>
<h5></h5>
<h3>Could you introduce your new collection, 'in conversation,' and explain the inspiration behind it?<strong><br><br></strong>
</h3>
<p>‘In Conversation’ is a series of abstract collages that will be displayed in Audo House new restaurant concept. The artworks are inspired by the architecture of Audo House itself — including the colours, textures and atmosphere. My approach toward materiality and response to my surroundings are both very intuitive, and I seek to unite these two worlds. With ‘In Conversation,’ my aim was to create an interactive conversation between the room, its guests and the artworks themselves.</p>
<h5></h5>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://audocph.com/blogs/news/featured-artist-ulla-bang</id>
    <published>2021-11-23T17:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2023-12-21T08:41:59+01:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://audocph.com/blogs/news/featured-artist-ulla-bang"/>
    <title>Featured Artist: Ulla Bang</title>
    <author>
      <name>Audo House</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<h3 data-mce-fragment="1">Ceramicist, Ulla Bang is known for her beautiful, handbuilt stoneware ceramics. Created using an ancient pottery technique, her works draw inspiration from forms and shapes discovered in everyday life. The Shapes Collection by Ulla Bang was created exclusively for Audo House and features an assortment of organic shapes and textures — designed to complement the bold, architectural lines of the house.</h3>
<p><img alt="" src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0600/3123/8322/files/P1013186_2_2048x2048.jpg?v=1654166618"></p>
<h5><strong></strong></h5>
<h3>Could you describe your creative background and how you came to work with ceramics?<br><br>
</h3>
<p>Art and design have always been a part of my life and can be traced back to my family’s background. My father was a sculptor from the Royal Academy of Art and worked as a sculptor, painter and ceramicist all his life. My mother also has been a great source of inspiration for me, as she is a maker of jewellery and all kinds of crafts. Therefore, it was natural that my childhood was full of arts and crafts, exhibitions, workshops and books.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><img alt="" src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0600/3123/8322/files/Journal_Template_4_2048x2048.png?v=1654167360"></p>
<p> </p>
<p>My father always liked to say that his work was determined by form and shape. Despite having gone to art school in the sixties, where performance art and expression were the dominant art form, he had no intention of “saying” something with his work. Art, to him, was guided by form and precision. To this day, I still love this approach and it has always influenced the ways in which I appreciate arts and crafts.</p>
<p>I began my artistic career in the theatre, working with props and costumes for puppet performances. Later, I trained as a theatre designer at Wimbledon School of Art in London. I spent three years focused on building my skills and expertise while making endless trips to art museums, theatre performances and various exhibitions across London. After graduation, I spent 10 years as a freelance theatre designer in Copenhagen, primarily working with children’s theatre, props and costume-making.</p>
<p>Around 2005, I changed direction and established my children’s wear label, UBANG. The brand is still an essential part of my business today, however, I’ve taken a step back in recent years to focus on clay and ceramics.</p>
<p>I was introduced to the world of clay when my daughter found my father’s old throwing wheel and wanted to give it a try. For me, it was a case of love at first sight. Working with clay through such a hands-on medium allowed me to create a series of series of pure, unconstrained artistic expressions. After a while, I took up handbuilt ceramics, which is my primary technique today.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><img alt="" src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0600/3123/8322/files/P1013305_2048x2048.jpg?v=1654167852"></p>
<h3>In your own words, what characterizes your artworks?<br><br>
</h3>
<p>My artworks are organic and free but also precise and detailed. I like my creations to challenge balance, to be free and unexpected in their form, but always end with a fine focused and precise top rim.</p>
<p> </p>
<h3>Where does your inspiration arise from?<strong><br><br></strong>
</h3>
<p>My inspiration arrives from the forms and shapes which I pass by in my everyday life. It can be anything — an artwork, a building or a dress; anything that catches my eye and piques my interest. I try to keep my mind open and let my hands and eyes do the work.<br><br>Often, my approach involves drawing a simple sketch and starting to sculpt. If I start placing too much intellectual thought and meaning into my creative process, I feel the spontaneous lightness disappear.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><img alt="" src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0600/3123/8322/files/Journal_Template_6_2048x2048.png?v=1654167771"></p>
<h5></h5>
<h3></h3>
<h3>What does it mean to be handbuilt and how is this achieved?<br><br>
</h3>
<p>All of my work is handbuilt stoneware ceramics — an ancient technique which uses simple tools rather than a pottery wheel. The technique itself is very basic, but it offers endless possibilities for the shape of the ceramic itself.</p>
<p>Handbuilt ceramics are crafted using carefully rolled-out coils stacked on top of each other. The coils are then gently smoothed out until the individual edges are no longer visible. The pieces are then shaped and sculpted from the bottom upwards. This is a long process and involves a lot of pushing, shaping, correcting and refining, with intermittent periods in which the clay must be left to dry.<br><br>Once the general shape has been built, I like to spend a lot of time finishing the top rim — evening the organic shapes and creating the surface texture. With the Shapes collection, I worked a lot using a “dot dot dot” texture. This is essentially a series of dots created using the pointed handle of one of my father’s old paintbrushes. I typically apply this technique after the clay has been left drying for some time, yet still has some residual softness. It’s a slow and meditative process which I enjoy a lot.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><img alt="" src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0600/3123/8322/files/Journal_Template_5_2048x2048.png?v=1654167673"></p>
<h5></h5>
<h3>
<strong><br></strong>What is the concept behind your newest collection, 'shapes'?<br><strong><br></strong>
</h3>
<p>The Shapes collection is defined by organic shapes, raw surfaces and interesting textures. The collection ranges from small, lidded containers to big, curvy vases and more sculptural pieces with curious holes. All the pieces in the collection are glazed on the side, while the exterior is left raw and untreated.<br><br>I have a personal fascination with lidded jars. They make you curious as you always want to lift the lid and look inside. The same applies to holes — you want to look through them and see the world from a new perspective. To me, curiosity is equal to inspiration. They both keep us interested in exploring.</p>
<p>With the Shapes collection, I hope to inspire others to embark on journeys of curiosity and exploration. The pieces within the collection are soft, feminine and joyous. Together, they form a still life of sorts — a portrait of organic shapes, natural tones and varied textures.</p>
<p> </p>
<h3>How has your collection been shaped or informed by the interiors of Audo House?<br><br>
</h3>
<p>Audo House is a space that is full of natural tones and textures, great design and strong lines. I wanted my collection to reflect the space’s rich colour tones using the natural colour palette of ceramic clay. By choosing to glaze only the inside of the individual ceramics, I could highlight the gentle warmth and beauty of raw clay. The collection’s organic and naturalistic shapes are a soothing complement to the strong, architectural lines of Audo House.<em> </em></p>
<div style="text-align: center;"><em><span style="font-weight: 400;"></span></em></div>
<div>
<span style="font-weight: 400;">Designed exclusively for Audo House, the </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">‘Shapes’ </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">collection by Ulla Bang is a sensuous exploration of proportion, texture and form through the medium of clay. </span><br><em><br><br></em>
</div>
<div style="text-align: center;"><em></em></div>
<div style="text-align: center;"><em></em></div>
<div style="text-align: center;"><em>Follow Ulla Bang on Instagram<span> </span><a title="here" href="https://www.instagram.com/ullabang_ceramics/">here</a></em></div>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://audocph.com/blogs/news/beyond-the-surface-exploring-light-and-shadow</id>
    <published>2021-11-23T16:30:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2023-12-21T08:41:59+01:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://audocph.com/blogs/news/beyond-the-surface-exploring-light-and-shadow"/>
    <title>Beyond The Surface exploring light and shadow</title>
    <author>
      <name>Audo House</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<div>
<h3 data-mce-fragment="1">Conceived and created from a mindset of combining minimalistic abstraction with timeless scandinavian aesthetics, Atelier Plateau's 15 unique art reliefs blend in with the walls to discreetly be a part of the surroundings. still, as the light changes during the day, the walls change - and shapes, colors, and shadow lines in the wall reliefs stand out uniquely depending on the time of day. </h3>
<br><img height="2048x2048" width="2048x2048" src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0600/3123/8322/files/TheAudo_BeyondTheSurfaceAtelierPlateau_Periodical_PhotographybyArminTehrani_25253AV_2525C3_2525A6rnisStudio_1_2048x2048.jpg?v=1637672599"><br><br>
</div>
<p class="">Atelier Plateau is a creative design studio exploring unique, handmade wall reliefs, based in Copenhagen, consisting of architect duo Anne Berthelsen and Mikkel Johnsen. All the art pieces they make focus on the interplay between light, shadow, and textures. With these conditions and depending on the light's movement within a particular space, each wall relief takes on a different expression. Atelier Plateau draws daily inspiration from Scandinavian design heritage and craftsmanship - striving to bring this into the creation of reliefs.</p>
<p class="">The series of wall reliefs is called Beyond the Surface and is anchored in how we experience surfaces, light, and the elements around us. With the explorations into light and shadow, we encourage the observer to spend time in the space to experience each wall relief's changing expressions as the time and conditions change. The interplay between the wall relief and the surroundings is essential. </p>
<p class=""><em>"We carefully study the existing materials, colors, and details of the site so that the surroundings and decor can inform each other. Our reliefs are in dialogue with the rooms they occupy as they change expression during the day, depending on how the light hits each unique, three-dimensional composition.", Mikkel Johnsen explains, and adds: "We are fascinated with the experience the different scales provide to the viewer and how the light travels across large surfaces to create a sense of spaciousness."</em></p>
<p class=""> </p>
<div><img alt="" src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0600/3123/8322/files/TheAudo_BeyondTheSurfaceAtelierPlateau_Periodical_PhotographybyArminTehrani_3AV_C3_A6rnisStudio_4_2048x2048.jpg?v=1637672726"></div>
<h3>
<br>Colors and materials<br><br>
</h3>
<p class="">The wall reliefs are made of wood materials painted with eco-friendly paint and plaster. The plateaus have various depths to create different light and shadow conditions in the construction of each relief. The colors are mixed by St. Leo from organic powder pigments, including several unique colors made especially for the collection to ensure complete synergy with Audo House interior palette.</p>
<h3><strong> </strong></h3>
<h3>The process<br><strong><br></strong>
</h3>
<p class="">The creative methodology of Atelier Plateau is anchored in a visual atlas of atmospheres, colors, materials, textures, and moments to create a departure point for the 'inspiration' phase. Continuing into the 'composing' phase, the architect duo experiments with forms, focusing on the interplay between light and shadow. From here, the art pieces are developed further in the 'detailing' phase, where the process goes beyond the form alone to a more in-depth exploration into colors and textures. Throughout each step, an attempt is made to maintain the balance of impression and expression subtly.</p>
<p class=""> </p>
<p class=""><img alt="" src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0600/3123/8322/files/Design_uden_navn_43_2048x2048.png?v=1637673136"></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://audocph.com/blogs/news/atelier-plateau-studio-visit</id>
    <published>2021-11-23T15:30:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2023-12-21T08:42:00+01:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://audocph.com/blogs/news/atelier-plateau-studio-visit"/>
    <title>Atelier Plateau Studio Visit</title>
    <author>
      <name>Audo House</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<div style="text-align: left;">
<h3 data-mce-fragment="1">During 3 days of design 2020, Audo House unveiled a new exhibition with danish architect and design duo atelier plateau, titled beyond the surface. the collaborative collection takes inspiration from Audo House new interior design concept and explores modernist form and colour through a series of limited-edition, handmade wall reliefs finished with St. Leo’s sustainable dolomite plaster. in celebration of the exhibition, we visited Atelier Plateau’s Copenhagen studio to observe Anne and Mikkel’s creative process and discuss the inspiration and philosophy behind their practice.</h3>
<br><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0600/3123/8322/files/MENU_TheAudo_PreviewMay29_03-2_62785fdf-cb29-4000-8da2-bf6a12c145c6.jpg?v=1637330025" style="float: none;">
</div>
<p> </p>
<h3>Please tell us about atelier plateau?<br><br>
</h3>
<p>We are a creative studio exploring the creation of unique, handmade wall reliefs. All the art pieces we make focus on the interplay between light, shadow and textures. With these conditions and depending on the movement of the light within a certain space, each wall relief takes on a different expression. Based in Copenhagen, our studio was established in the beginning of 2020 and we draw daily inspiration from Scandinavian design heritage and craftsmanship—striving to bring this into the development of our reliefs. Our vision is to encourage the observer to be present in the moment and to reflect. We believe that is an important gesture in today’s society.<br><br></p>
<div style="text-align: left;"><img style="float: none;" src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0600/3123/8322/files/MENU_TheAudo_PreviewMay29_03-2_1_2048x2048.jpg?v=1637330112"></div>
<h3></h3>
<h3>What are the main elements of your pieces?<br><br>
</h3>
<p>Our wall reliefs are all handmade in our studio. We use wood materials painted with eco-friendly paint and plaster. In the construction of each relief, we work with monochrome plateaus in various depths to create different light and shadow conditions. We always aim to add atmosphere to a space without demanding excessive attention, and instead find ways to go into dialogue with the space itself.</p>
<p> </p>
<h3>What is your process from concept to realisation?<br><br>
</h3>
<p>Our creative methodology is always anchored in a visual atlas of atmospheres, colours, materials, textures and moments to create a point of departure for our ‘inspiration’ phase. Continuing into our ‘composing’ phase, we experiment with form with a focus on the interplay between light and shadow. From here we develop our art pieces further in the ‘detailing’ phase, where our process goes beyond the form alone to deeper explorations into colours and textures. Throughout each phase we always strive to balance the impression and the expression in a subtle manner.</p>
<p> </p>
<div style="text-align: left;"><img style="float: none;" alt="" src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0600/3123/8322/files/DSC1408_75a1a59e-1c78-423a-90c2-404fc2785602_1024x1024.jpg?v=1637330154"></div>
<h3><strong></strong></h3>
<h3>Where do you draw inspiration?<br><br>
</h3>
<p>In our work we aim to have an equal sense of history, time and Genius Loci (a “Sense of Place”). In a time where our living and sensing is dominated by digital realms, our wall reliefs reintroduce a thousand-year-old tradition rooted in the physical sensing of our inhabited surroundings. Reliefs with motifs, patterns and tales, made of wood, are a well-known and cherished tradition around the world. With the explorations into light and shadow, we encourage the observer to spend time in the space to experience the changing expressions of each wall relief as the time and conditions in the space change. The interplay between the wall relief and the space itself is essential. In our bespoke Beyond The Surface collection, we strive to identify the sense of space and to study existing materials, colours and details.</p>
<p> </p>
<h3>How does your experience as architects impact or inspire your work as atelier plateau?<br><br>
</h3>
<p>With our professional background in architecture and spatial design, we perceive our wall reliefs as a natural continuation of our past work. We explore and challenge the experience and perception of our surroundings through our collection—as it is equally about the space as it is about form. These observations are anchored in how we experience surfaces, light, and the elements around us. We are fascinated with how a subtle change in a surface can transform the atmosphere in a space. As spatial practitioners, our aim is to orchestrate the balance between the proportions of the space, the light conditions and the remaining interior.</p>
<p> </p>
<div style="text-align: left;"><img style="float: none;" src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0600/3123/8322/files/MENU_TheAudo_PreviewMay29_03-2_0bfc25bd-2d7b-45d2-923b-f8f868d773da_2048x2048.jpg?v=1637330297"></div>
<h3>
<strong><br></strong>How do you approach your relationship as a creative duo and couple?<br><br>
</h3>
<p>We appreciate our ability to merge our working and private lives, as well as our family life. We strive to have a continuous creative process where both of us can equally contribute our individual ideas and aspirations. As partners, it is also essential that we share the same overall aims and have a common understanding of how and when we wish to work, finding a holistic balance in our everyday.</p>
<p> </p>
<h3>How have you approached your work during corona, and how has this time of isolation and reflection impacted you?</h3>
<p><br>During Corona it has become increasingly essential for us to be surrounded by physical objects that appeal to all of our senses, in a time where our external communication has been especially virtual. In our home we have therefore made more space for inspiration and brought materials and samples from our atelier to strengthen that process. The lockdown period has also given us the reflection time to concentrate and immerse ourselves in the Beyond The Surface collection.</p>
<p> </p>
<h3>How did the beyond the surface project come about?<strong><br><br></strong>
</h3>
<p>When we first received the invitation from Audo House, Beyond the Surface was immediately a collaboration we wanted to take on. Both because of the opportunity to develop a site-specific collection in such inspiring surroundings as Audo House, and as a means of experimenting with the textures and colours of St. Leo’s Dolomite Plaster. This bespoke collection holds the values that we appreciate and has culminated in a range of wall reliefs celebrating the different spaces and atmosphere at Audo House. The project has brought us both inspiration and joy.</p>
<p> </p>
<h3>Please describe the concept behind the collection.<strong><br><br></strong>
</h3>
<p>Beyond The Surface is an exploration of Modernist forms and colours—in synergy with Audo’s new interior design concept. Taking in the existing spaces of Audo House, we immediately felt inspired by all the architectural details. We closely studied the existing materials, colours and textures as an investigative process to inform our art pieces. Each wall relief has been developed for a specific location at Audo House and we have carefully selected the colours to work in harmony with their context. This dialogue between the spaces and our art pieces has been the backbone of our whole process. In combination with the form making, our collaboration with the talented team behind St. Leo has been a journey into new materiality and the art of mixing colours.</p>
<p> </p>
<h3>Tell us more about the materials and colours used in the collection.<br><br>
</h3>
<p>For Beyond The Surface, we have worked with St. Leo on a combination of existing Dolomite Plaster colours, as well as several custom hues made especially for the collection—each inspired by Audo’s Modernist interior design concept. The bold and rich red colour, for instance, draws upon the Bauhaus universe and also serves as a reference to the exterior facade of Audo House. When taken together, the colours of the wall reliefs blend into the existing context whilst creating dynamic accents. The artworks have been greatly impacted by the beautiful colours and textures from St. Leo, which provide unique and lively surfaces. All the colours were hand-mixed by St. Leo from natural, powder pigments and we have aimed to retain the material’s authenticity in each relief.</p>
<p> </p>
<h3>Are there any particular pieces in the collection that you are most excited about?<br><br>
</h3>
<p>Through this project we have been exploring larger scales than we are typically accustomed to. For instance we made a five-meter tall wall relief, which is our largest piece so far. We are fascinated with the experience the different scales provide to the viewer, and how the light travels across large surfaces to create a sense of spaciousness.</p>
<p> </p>
<h3>How does the beyond the surface collection relate to the interior design concept of audo house?<br><br>
</h3>
<p>Beyond The Surface as a concept originates from Audo’s new interior design, which unveils during 3 Days of Design. Each wall relief has been developed for a specific location at Audo House and we have carefully selected the colours to work in harmony with their context. This dialogue between the spaces and our art pieces has been the backbone of our whole process.</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://audocph.com/blogs/news/julie-haverkamp-at-audo-house</id>
    <published>2021-11-23T15:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2023-12-21T08:42:00+01:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://audocph.com/blogs/news/julie-haverkamp-at-audo-house"/>
    <title>Julie Haverkamp At Audo House</title>
    <author>
      <name>Audo House</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<h3>As a part of 3 days of design, Audo House unveils a new exhibition with dutch artist julie haverkamp, titled “in-between moments”. the collaborative collection draws inspiration from the passage of time, dreaming about the far away and searching for the space in between. our conversation with Julie touches on her process and philosophy behind the collection.<br><br>
</h3>
<p><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0600/3123/8322/files/Julie-TheAUDO_SimoneFrank-25_1024x1024.jpg?v=1637846505" alt=""></p>
<p> </p>
<h3>Could you tell us a little bit about how you discovered your way into art?</h3>
<p> </p>
<div data-block-type="2" id="block-822ba270b1a9fb216d28">
<p>It all started when I was very little - I was always drawing as I was growing up in a creative family, with both grandparents being architects.</p>
<p>When I started my studies at the Amsterdam Fashion Institute, I was under a lot of stress and pressure to succeed with my projects, which made drawing a way to become calm again. It became my go-to tool to ensure I survived. In my third year, I started a minor at an Art academy ArtEZ, in Zwolle, where a whole new world opened up for me. I learned some new techniques and started painting full series of portraits. I used more colour and texture, which allowed me to push myself even further. There was just one thing that hindered my creativity - perfection. I was always holding on to the perfection of the photo, to the extent that I missed the freedom of my own creativity.</p>
<p>There was a point when I was looking back at all the work I had made in the past, and I started thinking of ways to challenge myself. I had to find a new way of expressing my emotions, but with less perfection. I began channelling my emotions through deep colours and abstract shapes, playing a never-ending story.</p>
<p>Finally, painting had become the ultimate way of expressing my emotions.</p>
<h3>
<br><br>How does your family background in architecture impact or inspire your art?</h3>
<h5><strong> </strong></h5>
<p>Growing up in a creative family taught me a new perspective on how things are created and how ideas morph into reality. I was always involved in projects my family was working on, so I understood that everything requires hard work. Growing up in a creative family with a background in fashion and architecture showed me that I needed to work hard in order to achieve something I was dreaming about.</p>
<p>It also gave me an eye for detail, which comes in handy when I’m looking for inspiration or working on an art piece. I love to be inspired by architecture, interior design and fashion, therefore I can say without a shadow of a doubt that it strongly influences my art.<br><br></p>
<p><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0600/3123/8322/files/juliehaverkamp_periodical_1024x1024.jpg?v=1635767271" alt=""></p>
<h3>
<strong><br></strong>How would you describe your artworks?<strong><br><br></strong>
</h3>
<p>I think my artworks are abstract, but they also carry a lot of emotion. As I use painting to navigate my way out of the craziness, I also think the paintings can bring some sort of serenity to the observer.</p>
<p> </p>
<h3>Where do you draw inspiration?<br><br>
</h3>
<p>I love travelling to destinations, where I can discover new shapes, moods and colours. I always take pictures of crazy angles or small accents that catch my eye.<br><br>There are also some artists I simply can’t let go of. For example, Mark Rothko, who was a very emotional artist searching for the intimate space between the painting and the observer. I always found his ability to take the observer inside the painting incredibly fascinating. I also tried to translate his way of painting and his skilful use of colours into my art.<br><br>Another favourite of mine is Alexander Calder. I admire the way he played with movement and shapes, as a glance from a different perspective allows us to see something new in his works. He translated incredible playfulness into his use of primary colours and abstract shapes, and, not to forget, the overarching balance that can always be found in his work.<br><br></p>
<p> </p>
<h3>Could you let us in on your work process?<br><br>
</h3>
<p>I never start with a plan - my process begins by making canvas from untreated cotton. Then I start with the first layer of the background. The colour I choose depends on the particular mood or emotion I’m experiencing at that moment. Then I dilute some colours with a lot of water in order to paint very thin layers over each other. In this phase, I tend to let myself go. There will be layers upon layers of brighter colours to create depth. In the second phase, I will start layering shapes, which I create using a small art knife and tape. In this phase, I work with different kinds of mediums to add some texture to those shapes. In the last phase, I finalize the artwork by adding some accents or connecting the lines to encourage the eye to travel over the painting.<br><br><br></p>
<h3>Could you please describe the concept behind the in-between moments?<br><br>
</h3>
<h5></h5>
<p>The concept behind the collection is closely linked to my thoughts during the COVID pandemic. I was thinking about the extreme lack of intimacy, travel and touch. Making the collection was a sort of a remedy for me, which allowed me to dream and reflect on myself, thinking about all the good and bad things I’ve been through. I remembered my travels to the old family house in the south of France, where we always went for summer. Audo House reminds me of that place, mostly due to the remarkably bright red colour of the facade, and the warm feeling I get when I enter it. At these kinds of places, we all experience different moments - we will always be “in-between moments”.</p>
<p>The collection is called “In-between Moments”, and it is inspired by the passage of time, dreaming of the far away and searching for the space in between.<br><br>I created a collection, in which the eye will travel into different layers and textures of the painting. I dare the observer to touch the artwork with their eyes.</p>
<p> </p>
<h3>How long does it take to create an art piece from the initial idea to the finished art piece?<br><br>
</h3>
<p>It’s difficult to pinpoint the exact time frame it takes to create an art piece. Sometimes I work longer on the background, and other times I will layer the shapes more. When I was working on my collection for Audo House, I was pretty content with having a work schedule. I could feel the flow of the energy, which made it easier for me to work on it for a longer time.<br><br></p>
<p><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0600/3123/8322/files/Julie_Haverkamp_3DD_2021_at_The_Audo_Shot_by_Vaernis_Studio-LR-3_1024x1024.jpg?v=1635767517" alt=""></p>
<h3>
<strong><br></strong>How have you approached your work during corona, and how has this time of isolation and reflection impacted you?<br><br>
</h3>
<h5></h5>
<p>I think for a lot of people it was important to focus on their creativity. We all had to find a medium through which we could express our emotions and feelings about what was happening in the world.</p>
<p>At the time, I had just finished the art minor I mentioned earlier, so I had time to really challenge myself. The standstill presented me with an opportunity to experiment with different materials, colours, layers and shapes. While my creativity was evolving in a positive direction, there were also difficult moments, when I felt lonely being on my own in the atelier. </p>
<p>I think this crazy period made me think about the things I miss. I missed real human contact, the intimacy with loved ones, the real touch of textures and materials, travelling to inspire myself, and experiencing the unexpected things that happen once in a while.</p>
<p> </p>
<h3>How have you approached your work during corona, and how has this time of isolation and reflection impacted you? how does your collection relate to the interior design concept of Audo House?<span><br><br></span>
</h3>
<p>I visited Audo House last October, on a trip with my mom, and it just felt like home. It was so warm and inviting, so this is an aspect that I came back to when creating the collection. I like to be inspired by different lines and shapes found in interior design. The collection was inspired by Audo Copenhagen and the mood of Audo House, and then it came together as a whole.<br><br></p>
<p><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0600/3123/8322/files/Design_uden_navn_50_1024x1024.png?v=1637846548" alt=""></p>
<p><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0600/3123/8322/files/Julie-TheAUDO_SimoneFrank-29-3_1024x1024.jpg?v=1635767948" alt=""></p>
</div>
<div data-block-type="47" id="block-d727741201df4e1cd400">
<div><hr></div>
</div>
<div data-block-type="2" id="block-17b779ecc10ce85f2713">
<div>
<p>“In-between Moments” pieces are for sale in-store.</p>
</div>
</div>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://audocph.com/blogs/news/interview-with-artist-manuela-guidarini</id>
    <published>2021-11-23T12:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2023-12-21T08:41:58+01:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://audocph.com/blogs/news/interview-with-artist-manuela-guidarini"/>
    <title>Interview with artist, Manuela Guidarini</title>
    <author>
      <name>Audo House</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<h3>We have had the pleasure to talk with Manuela Guidarini and get to know her and her work better. Guidarini is an Italian self-taught artist with an interest in geometric shapes and compositions, which also shows in her beautiful pieces.</h3>
<div style="text-align: start;"><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0600/3123/8322/files/Ombre_no.1_-_still_life_1_1024x1024.jpg?v=1680506011" alt="Arist looking at her own art piece, having her back showing in a beautiful black silk dress" style="float: none;"></div>
<p> </p>
<h3>Could you briefly introduce yourself and tell us about your background?</h3>
<p><br>I was born and raised in Italy. My memories from that time are somewhat intense and agitated. After completing my master in Architecture, I stepped away from my roots and moved abroad. I first settled in London where I worked as an interior architect. My time there was extraordinary but very intense. After moving to Copenhagen in 2019, I finally had the opportunity to unwind and start an introspective journey that brought me closer to Asian culture and values. I started painting as a ritual and found peace in the calmness of rigorous and simple geometrical shapes. For someone who has had a chaotic childhood, creating art that is rigorous and minimalistic is a way to find order in a world that, at times, feels overwhelming and uncontrollable. Focusing on the essential elements of my work has allowed me to create a sense of balance that I felt was lacking growing up. Unconsciously, I strive to infuse my art with a sense of calmness and serenity, inviting the viewer to slow down and contemplate the present moment.</p>
<p> </p>
<h3>Can you shed some light on what paved your way to become an artist? </h3>
<p><br>I have always been much more comfortable expressing myself through graphic art. In my early years, I experimented with a number of mediums, from clay to etching, all the way to watercolour. I simply love observing and responding to an idea I want to develop - it can be simple elements like shading, movement, contrast - and watch it take shape on canvas. I think that when I gave myself the permission to become an artist rather than just an architect, I was allowing myself to be more authentic. My art features many topics related to architecture and geometry, like balance and stillness. It is also a reflection of my personal values and beliefs. Art is a powerful tool for self-expression and healing and it has surely helped me process and make sense of some experiences in my past.</p>
<p> </p>
<h3>Where do you draw inspiration from for art pieces How has your background in architecture shaped and influenced your work as a painter?</h3>
<div>
<strong><br></strong>Studying architecture changed everything for me. In particular, being exposed to Rationalist and Modernist architecture - very geometrically defined design with little ornamentation - left such an important mark on my aesthetic that eventually bled into any graphic representation. This series of values didn’t just affect me as a painter, but as human. Stripping away all unessential elements has become a very big part of my daily choices in general.     </div>
<div>
<br><br>
<h3>In your own words what characterizes your artworks?</h3>
</div>
<p><br>I paint abstract canvases where geometric shapes form fragmented architectural structures. I strip away unessential elements and focus on the interplay of form and colour. I am very influenced by artists with a particular taste for muted tones - like Vilhelm Hammershøi - and this has intuitively shaped my signature colour combination of reds, sands and blacks.<br><br></p>
<div style="text-align: start;"><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0600/3123/8322/files/Untitled_no.3_-_detail_1024x1024.jpg?v=1680615267" style="float: none;"></div>
<p> </p>
<h3>What does your creative work process typically look like?<strong> </strong>
</h3>
<p><br>Every piece is individually conceived and crafted. Intuitively, I am always guided by the same principles, proportions and tones. I have a beautiful pin board at home that I like to populate with images that captivate me, from colours to patterns, to atmospheres and architectural references. When I have a strong idea, I generally sketch it by hand and immediately understand if it is something I wish to develop and that intuitively represents me. Then I move onto a digital software and study the proportions and tones more carefully before moving to the canvas where I generally spend a long time with tape and rulers. Obsessively so, I take great pleasure from crafting shapes and volumes. Working on each piece gives me focus and peace. </p>
<p> Explore Manuela's art pieces, available at Audo House</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://audocph.com/blogs/news/tora-frogner-at-audo-house</id>
    <published>2021-11-23T11:30:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2023-12-21T08:41:59+01:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://audocph.com/blogs/news/tora-frogner-at-audo-house"/>
    <title>Tora Frogner at Audo House</title>
    <author>
      <name>Audo House</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<h3 data-mce-fragment="1">Tora Frogner (b. 1991) is an up-and-coming Copenhagen-based, Norwegian artist who works with sculpture, site-specific installations and mixed-media. She has exhibited in Europe and North America, and her art has been sold to buyers in Australia, France, Spain and Norway. Additionally, she is represented at BOON in Paris, Sirin Gallery and Audo House in Copenhagen.</h3>
<p> </p>
<p> <img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0600/3123/8322/files/5_97ff9ca3-0f14-452e-afde-252d46bf4ae9.png?v=1651667915" alt=""></p>
<h5></h5>
<p>Tora is co-editor of the art book Offentlighedens Rum (Spaces of the Public, 2018), a collection of images and texts reflecting upon the use and stories of public spaces with contributions from Mamma Andersson, Olafur Eliasson, SUPERFLEX, Tal R, Frode Grytten and 23 other Nordic artists. </p>
<p>Frogner works with a diversity of materials and often returns to simple materiality such as paper and clay in her art. In her practice, Tora Frogner captures atmospheres in nature using abstract forms and solitary postures to create a landscape of an odd existence, indecisive of whether its force is one of vitality or decay.</p>
<p>We met with Tora in her studio to discuss inspiration, experimentation and the process of creating her newest collection, the Growth series.</p>
<h3>
<strong><br></strong>Can you shed some light on how you have paved your way as an artist and creator?<br><strong><br></strong>
</h3>
<p class="">I’ve always experienced a powerful attraction to the aesthetic field in general, including many different types of creative work, such as dance, theatre, architecture and academia.<br><br>I still enjoy partaking in and seeking inspiration from all of these various fields, however, visual arts have always formed the backbone of my practice. A natural channel through which I find ways to process the world around me, as it were.<br><br>Creating has always felt very intuitive for me. It is a means through which I can explore my curiosity through play and creative experimentation. Creating has helped me come to terms with the realization that the world is a place filled with opportunities and untold stories — rather than a closed door.</p>
<p class=""> </p>
<h3>How has your background in architecture and material studies helped shape or inspire your artistic output? <br><br>
</h3>
<p>My architectural background has had a lasting impact on the ways in which I perceive space and reflect on its importance. My studies have helped to train my eye and develop my critical capabilities. As a result, I<span> </span><em>see</em><span> </span>things differently, for better or for worse. As a consequence, I am deeply interested in how we, as humans,<span> </span><em>make<span> </span></em>ourselves in the world, live with the world and create spaces and objects out of the materials surrounding us.<br><br>It’s challenging to pinpoint exactly what it is that you learn when working within a specific field, but I believe that both the tacit and explicit academic knowledge I acquired have shaped my practice in many ways. Conversely, I believe that my background in architecture has helped shape how I build the narrative of an artwork and my general approach when working with the materials I am drawn to.<br><br></p>
<p> </p>
<h3>What kind of emotion or ambience do you seek to capture in your artworks?<br><br>
</h3>
<p>In my art, I try to capture the atmosphere of nature as materialised portraits — stills of movement and time. The expressions of my artworks refer to geological landscapes, corrals, wood or buds about to break out in blossom.<br><br>I am interested in creating artefacts by highlighting abstract forms and textures, which then build a connection between nature and the perception of nature. Just as nature does, human bodies grow, emerge and eventually decompose, transitioning into something else entirely. Similarly, things in the natural world have their life span, although this timeline can be much faster or slower than that of humans.</p>
<p> <img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0600/3123/8322/files/4.png?v=1651668058" alt=""></p>
<h5></h5>
<h3>
<strong><br></strong>Could you describe the concept behind the growth series?<br><strong><br></strong>
</h3>
<p>In my<em><span> </span>Growth<span> </span></em>Series, I work with the concept of the vase as a pure shape. The vase made from clay is a primordial object, built and used for containment as well as adornment through the ages. I love these old archetypes and traditions that have a kind of universal feeling to them.<br><br>Specifically,<span> </span><em>Growth</em><span> </span>is a reflection of the limits of materiality. The sculptures are made from unglazed stoneware, where the pigments from the clay create the colours and patterns.</p>
<p> </p>
<h3>Where did you draw inspiration from for the growth series?</h3>
<p> </p>
<p>The question of inspiration is always challenging because the answer, from my perspective, is quite varied. I don’t have a specific reference, object or place, from which I draw inspiration and my works often arise from a collection of feelings, drawn together from various life situations and experiences.<br><br>I do tend to lean towards the contrast between the robust and fragile, the soft and hard. Moreover, I seek to explore the idea that there is an aspect of time, growth and degeneration in everything which surrounds us.<br><br>Landscapes often inspire me, because these open spaces contain a mixture of many materials, colours and textures, but also narratives and stories told.</p>
<p> </p>
<h5></h5>
<h5></h5>
<h5></h5>
<h5></h5>
<p><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0600/3123/8322/files/3.png?v=1651667999" alt=""></p>
<h5></h5>
<h3>
<strong><br></strong>What does your work process typically look like?<br><br>
</h3>
<h5></h5>
<p>I dream of having a structured workflow when working in my atelier, but I can never seem to make it work in actuality. Strangely enough, I believe that the best works I have produced so far, have been born from a moment of chance. Yet, behind these moments, exists hours of work, discarded shapes and sketches which I am not satisfied with.<br><br>My process behind creation is very open-ended. When I go to my studio to experiment, I try to surrender to the ambiguity of the creative process. Sometimes this takes the form of sketching but oftentimes I allow my hands to lead, gradually forming a concept or shape that becomes clearer as the artwork evolves.<br><br>I also set aside time for rest, allowing myself to go out for walks, read and organize. Some of my artworks are constructed intuitively and created as part of a dialogue with the material. Other times, my projects have been residing in my mind for years, resting until I eventually coax them out and bring them to life.</p>
<p> <br><br></p>
<h3>What makes minimalism or simplicity appealing? and how do you work with the concept of minimalism in your work?<br><br>
</h3>
<p>I believe that simplicity is so appealing to us because it allows details to take the centre of attention. However, simplicity is perhaps most compelling when viewed in communion with high-quality materials and engaging shapes. Without attention to detail and craftsmanship, minimalistic objects or interiors can quickly become boring or alienating.<br><br>Good design is often perceived as an aesthetic bombardment of colour, shape and tactility. However, I also believe that it can be important to allow the senses to rest, through a sense of simplicity or minimalism. When done correctly, sparsity can become a type of meditation.<br> </p>
<p><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0600/3123/8322/files/6.png?v=1651668098" alt=""></p>
<h5></h5>
<h3><strong> </strong></h3>
<h3>What was the timeline like when creating the growth series?<br><strong><br></strong>
</h3>
<p><span>Each piece in the <em>Growth </em>series took between 6 to 8 weeks to create. From building up to carving and drying, the act of creating a sculpture can be a very slow process. I always begin with an idea of how the final piece is going to look — the shape, colour and clays, however, there is a natural sense of evolution and fluidity that occurs throughout the building process. Every sculpture is unique and I view each work as a small creature that grows together with me as I work.</span></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://audocph.com/blogs/news/josephine-aune-at-audo-house</id>
    <published>2021-11-23T11:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2023-12-21T08:42:00+01:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://audocph.com/blogs/news/josephine-aune-at-audo-house"/>
    <title>Josephine Aune at Audo House</title>
    <author>
      <name>Audo House</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<h3>We had the pleasure to talk with the s<span data-mce-fragment="1">wedish artist </span>Josephine Aune about her beautiful artwork.</h3>
<h3><img alt="" src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0600/3123/8322/files/Photographer_Fanny_Radvik_3_2048x2048.jpg?v=1637673659"></h3>
<h3></h3>
<h3>Could you tell us a little bit about how you discovered your way into art?</h3>
<h3></h3>
<p class="">A new chapter started when the lines came into my life in 2017, and from there I’ve followed my intuition and I’ve let the lines guide my path forward ever since. I believe that everything happens for a reason and the lines showed me something new to explore. A new way of living. It’s like my soul was longing to express myself in a new way and the lines were flowing through my hands. Trusting the process and letting go, following the heart and creating space for magic to happen. I’ve always loved to create and paint a lot as a child and I can see lines in old paintings from my childhood… so, in a very nonlinear way, just as life is, I found my way back to my essence, re-discovering art and my expression. And it changes all the time. To have the courage to listen to the heart and follow the intuition, to follow the passion and to trust the process and let life unfold.</p>
<h3>
<br><br>How does your experience in the fashion industry impact or inspire your art?</h3>
<h3><strong></strong></h3>
<h3></h3>
<p class="">I know that my years working in fashion paved the way for creating feelings and inspiring. In styling and creating fashion stories, I always wanted to portray and create a feeling of a real girl, a woman in clothes you really could picture yourself wearing in everyday life and draw inspiration from. I was very detail-oriented, but also liked to focus on the big picture while working at ELLE, and that’s the way I still am in my art and in life. It’s all in the details. I really put my heart and soul into everything I create, so creating art was another way of channeling my energy and creativity. The connections with other creatives in fashion and interior are a gift. Everything changes all the time and that’s true in fashion, life, and art.  </p>
<h3>
<strong><br><br></strong>How would you describe your artworks?</h3>
<h3></h3>
<p class="">Feelings on paper, line language, dance, like line poems that create emotions. Simplicity, ease, calmness, harmony, beauty, freedom, soothing, something like jazz… To hear words from people who see and feel the lines is so beautiful, and what you see and feel in a line shifts. I’ve done a series called “Emotions” and I featured words I’ve received about my art in the catalog. The connection with the people who connect with me and feel drawn to the lines is so special. “…It’s like taking a deep breath,” says a part of a message from a man in Paris, or “It’s like music. Like a piece of classical music on paper.”</p>
<p data-rte-preserve-empty="true" class=""> <img alt="" src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0600/3123/8322/files/Photographer_Fanny_Radvik__8_2048x2048.jpg?v=1637673698"></p>
<h3><strong></strong></h3>
<h3>Where do you draw inspiration?</h3>
<h3></h3>
<p class="">Oh, I draw inspiration from so many things for my art and also my whole life! Beauty is all around, we’re surrounded by beauty if we lift our gaze and start to notice even the smallest little things… Other creative expressions inspire me even more to be myself - everyone has their unique gifts to share. Art, people, books, interior, fashion, music, spirituality, and conversations. It’s amazing how connected we are with others if we slow down and take our time to really listen and connect on a deeper level. Taking walks, being in nature, and soaking up the sun, I’m very inspired by light and the beauty light reflects onto everything. I also love being in the water, swimming, and breathing. These things are a lovely way to connect and find inspiration from within. So many new ideas arise from that calm place… To pause, to ground me with meditation is a way of clearing and connecting from within to see what’s there. It’s a beautiful place if you tend and nurture your inner landscape.</p>
<p data-rte-preserve-empty="true" class=""> </p>
<h3>Could you let us in on your work process?</h3>
<h3></h3>
<p class="">My process is very intuitive and the lines are coming through me, often in a single, sweeping motion, like a dance, and the pencil stays connected with the surface. It’s like a language transformed onto the paper surface and I just follow the flow, which is where I lose track of time. A blank, beautiful piece of paper, and from there I’ll see and feel what wants to come through, flow through me at that moment. That present moment. It’s a meditative state, and the act of creating is a form of meditation for me. Sometimes, I’ll close my eyes, so it's a very intuitive and organic process. Sometimes creating for hours, or just for a brief moment, creating one or a few lines… I love the feeling of paper, and I carefully choose the paper I work with. Often I opt for handmade cotton paper or Arches satin paper. <br><br><br></p>
<h3><strong></strong></h3>
<h3>Do you think each artwork connects with every person differently?<br><br>
</h3>
<p class="">I truly believe that when you see your line just now, you feel it. The line speaks to the heart and soul in a very special way and I know every line is and will be where it’s meant to be. Everything contains energy, and when you see a line, you feel something special within you. It’s a part of me put on paper, and I feel so connected with all my artworks in a very special way, and the personal connection I have with people and who find their unique line is so dear to me. I’m very grateful for that - the personal connection and conversations before the purchase of my original artwork.<br><br></p>
<h3>In your opinion, why do people find simplicity so appealing? </h3>
<h3><strong> </strong></h3>
<p class="">I can sense and see a shift now - people are slowing down and they have begun to listen more to their intuition and what the heart really wants. Quality over quantity. More ease and connecting with the present moment, really listening and taking it a bit slower. The longing for simplicity in a fast-paced</p>
<p class="">world with a lot of information, change, and impressions is a longing to connect within and to clear space for more authenticity. The lines can bring a sense of that simplicity, that stillness, and calm that’s very soothing for the mind and for the soul. If you look closely and also let yourself really feel, there’s a lot of harmony and beauty to be found in simplicity. We can explore our own emotions in that space and also, simplicity makes space for rest and creativity.<br><br></p>
<div><img alt="" src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0600/3123/8322/files/Photographer_Fanny_Radvik_5_1024x1024.jpg?v=1637673739"></div>
<p class=""> </p>
<div></div>
<p class=""><img alt="" src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0600/3123/8322/files/Photographer_Fanny_Radvik_4_2048x2048.jpg?v=1637674126"></p>
<p class="">Photography by Fanny Rådvik</p>
<p class=""> </p>
<span>Josephine Aune's </span><span>pieces are for sale in-store.</span>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://audocph.com/blogs/news/aterlier-cph-studio-visit</id>
    <published>2021-11-23T10:30:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2023-12-21T08:41:59+01:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://audocph.com/blogs/news/aterlier-cph-studio-visit"/>
    <title>Aterlier Cph Studio Visit</title>
    <author>
      <name>Audo House</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<div id="block-c2924ba26ee95fe4f3ab" data-block-type="2" class="sqs-block html-block sqs-block-html">
<div class="sqs-block-content">
<h3>We visited Atelier Cph studio while creating their new collection `assemble`debuting at Audo House on 19th November.</h3>
<p><strong><img height="2048x2048" width="2048x2048" src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0600/3123/8322/files/Design_uden_navn_47_2048x2048.png?v=1637676888"></strong></p>
<h3>ATELIER CPH ON ASSEMBLE:<br><br>
</h3>
<p class="">The new collection is based on the concept of manipulating fabrics, resulting in a collection of 28 new art prints. For the 2021 collection ‘Assemble´ we take inspiration from the feminist textile artist movement, which challenges the distinction between textiles and fine art. We do this by embracing techniques that were traditionally relegated to “women’s crafts”, such as sewing and quilting.</p>
<p class="">Since the first Atelier Cph collection, we have sustained an ongoing experiment with textiles which has greatly influenced our design direction through the years. While abstract in composition, the techniques for this collection vary from hand stitching, sewing, layering fabrics to different folding techniques. All pieces are made from leftover textiles, scraps of yarn from secondhand shops and recycled fabrics, demonstrating an honest use of materials. </p>
<p class="">Piecing together materials as a form of collage, the constructed geometric patterns reflect a simple modern expression. We hope this collection inspires you and that these fabric collages will add a new dimension to your walls.<br><br></p>
<p class=""><img alt="" src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0600/3123/8322/files/Design_uden_navn_49_2048x2048.png?v=1637677351"></p>
<p class=""><img alt="" src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0600/3123/8322/files/Design_uden_navn_46_2048x2048.png?v=1637676880"></p>
</div>
</div>
<div id="block-43c88d680d72a83a1cc3" data-block-type="2" class="sqs-block html-block sqs-block-html">
<div class="sqs-block-content">
<p class=""><br>Immerse yourself in the mesmerizing, tactile universe of ‘Assemble’ until midt December. Visitors will be invited to experience a series of exclusive prints and limited artworks by Atelier Cph at Audo Library. All pieces can be bough in our concept shop.</p>
</div>
</div>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
</feed>
